DM: I'll start.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay, go for it.
DM: Okay. Um,
DM: the color of the desert, however, pales in comparison to the vividness of your night ingredients.
DM: Um,
DM: something seems to have changed since you left Tokra.
DM: In the past, these dreams are rare, maybe a few times a year, but now every night takes you to a new landscape.
DM: Some of them are familiar from your childhood.
DM: A lush forest, in autumn, leaves turning golden, high peaks surrounding you.
DM: An island in the middle of an ocean with nothing but a single dark, tall tower standing on it.
DM: A tall, green hill, perfectly round, with small white flowers growing on it, surrounded by desert.
DM: Others are new and just flashes quicker than you can keep track of.
DM: A boat racked by waves, s- un- surprisingly to you, ma- seemingly made of stone.
DM: An impossible castle floating in the air above an expansive patchwork of small farms and cities.
DM: A vast, endless, expansive forest as far as the eye can see.
DM: But there's one that keeps returning night after night.
DM: A red sandstone mesa in a rocky desert, a small, clear oasis sheltering in the shadow of its cliffs.
Kenzo: Say that one again.
DM: A l- a red sandstone mesa in the, in a rocky desert, a small, clear oasis sheltering in the shadow of its cliffs.
DM: As you approach Karawa, the first thing you see from a distance in the morning light is a red sandstone mesa standing above the rocky desert ground.
DM: The desert flowers grow thickly here, scrubby, thorny plants bursting in color in the late spring before the heat of summer dries up the ground.
DM: But you hardly notice as your steps slow, then stop, and you realize that you are staring at an image out of your dreams.
DM: A temple is carved into the side of the mesa, and extends from it.
DM: The oasis is enclosed in a stone pool and surrounded by swaying palms.
DM: There's a small village that seems to have sprung up around, of mud houses and narrow streets, punctured by a few larger buildings and a large sandstone plaza.
DM: All of this has grown up from the desert of your dreams.
DM: A bustling tavern caravan saray stands on the outskirts of town.
DM: But take away the buildings, and the scene in front of you is unmistakably one you have seen many times over the past week of travel.
DM: Unsure of what it might mean, but drawn by an immediate connection to this place that seems at once deeply familiar and completely new, you start to head down in towards town,
DM: uh, heading down, uh, towards the caravan saray to find a room for the night,
DM: thinking about what this might mean.
DM: As you approach, you hear f- ahead of you, shouts and cries of help, breaking your reverie and snapping your attention to something that seems quite far ahead.
DM: A giant beast, two of them, hyena-like in form, but much larger than any hyena you've seen, charging
DM: into the village, people shouting,
DM: and cries as the villagers scatter in the face of these, uh, beasts appearing.
DM: And I'm gonna leave you there.
Kenzo: [laughs]
Kenzo: Cool. Um, Tim, really quick.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: So what, what was the name again of the...
Kenzo: So I'm, I'm, I'm there, and now I'm gonna go look for the temple, right?
DM: Uh, yeah, the Temple of Shakun is what you're looking for.
Kenzo: The person-
Kenzo: And what's the name of... Yep.
DM: Uh, Seeker Candrosa is the, is the person that you would be looking for, who's, like, the head of the temple.
Kenzo: Okay. Perfect.
Kenzo: Great. So you got it.
Kenzo: My name is, my name, my character's name is Kenzo.
DM: Kenzo. It's awesome. I like it.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: Okay. So send me a, um,
DM: uh, send me a, a token, by the way.
DM: Just email it to me. Send me an image of your guy.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Uh-
Kenzo: I haven't been able to find a good one yet, but, uh-
Unknown: Okay
Unknown: ...
DM: I'll, I'll see if I can try to find one.
DM: Uh, I'm going to, um-
Kenzo: You can use a random one if there's a random one for now.
DM: Yeah, I'll, I'll, I'll do something like that.
DM: You'll just be, like, a plain character.
Unknown: Um-
Unknown: That's fine.
DM: So you should leave the breakout room now.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: And...
DM: Mike, join your breakout room now.
Seeker: It's happening.
DM: Oops, where did I...
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Recording.
Delwath: This is very confusing.
Delwath: Yeah, this is very confusing. [laughs]
DM: The breakout rooms?
Delwath: Nah, just the tech setup.
Unknown: It's good.
DM: In the past few months, you've settled into a routine in the village.
DM: After the Dunmari got over the shock of seeing a real elf in their mists, probably the first one many of them had ever seen in their lives, and learned you could be useful around the village, you found lodging in the top of a small,
DM: top floor of a small house above the tea hou- above a, a small house above a tea house,
DM: and began exploring what you could of, of these mysteries of, of Shakun.
DM: The village is small, but seems to suit your needs for now.
DM: The oasis, surrounded by a short marble wall, is the center of town, and the shade of the swaying palms dotting the plaza around it is a pleasant place to pass the time out of the heat.
DM: Surrounding the oasis, there are small clusters of mud houses and narrow streets that stretch in three dirac- directions, while to the south stands the imposing edifice of the Temple of Shakun,
DM: partially carved into the red cliffs of the mesa to the south of town.
DM: Uh, you haven't been...
DM: You've been, uh, you know, asking around about the, the temple, and there's- A number of, like, lay accolades and, and other sort of people
DM: associated with it who are perfectly happy to say they're associated with it.
DM: And you do occasionally meet, um, see, and I've talked to a few times in the past, uh, Speaker Candrosa, who's the sort of public face, um, of the temp-
Unknown: Right.
DM: People do join.
DM: Um, there are, you know,
DM: uh, you've at least heard, although you don't have...
DM: You haven't heard firsthand from anybody of initiation ceremonies, usually a few times a year.
DM: But they're, they're secret.
DM: It's sort of like a combination of a monastery and the Freemasons.
DM: So it's not... The existence of it isn't secret, and, you know, people talk about their affiliation with it occasionally, but what actually goes along, goes on behind
DM: the-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... edifice of the, of the temple is unclear.
DM: Um, your lodging is at the edge of town,
DM: near the sprawling caravanserai that serves as, um, a marketplace and social center for travelers, and the place where you shop and, you know, um, a sort of trading area.
DM: During the winter months, not that many people pass through, um, because most of the Dunmar are out with their herds, um, when there's the, the rains and, and the desert is more
DM: hospitable.
DM: Um, but in the past few weeks, traffl- traffic has increased.
DM: You even heard rumors of a halfling who arrived a few days ago alone, which is unusual.
DM: However, more troubling in the past couple of weeks have been the attacks.
DM: Rarely if ever do wild animals venture into town, but twice in the past two weeks, small packs of hyenas, wild with furry, fury, have charged into town looking for
Unknown: prey.
DM: These are... The attacks are the talk of the town, and your status in the eyes of many have gone up after you helped drive off one, the hyenas in the first attack.
DM: Um, you're often known around town as just the elf, or elf, since, you know, most people have-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... never seen. You're the only elf anywhere in, in 100 miles, as far as you know.
DM: And this is on your mind as you prepare for the day, um, above the, in your room above the teahouse, when you hear out the window cries
DM: of, "Help, help," and, "Somebody get the elf."
DM: And that is where
DM: we'll leave.
Delwath: Okay.
DM: Just waiting for Mike to come back.
Kenzo: In D&D Beyond, is there a place to find, uh, kind of, uh, tokens?
DM: Not really.
Unknown: Um...
Kenzo: I have a hard time finding, like, a good, uh, thing to search for that, like,
Kenzo: has, uh, some good just random images.
DM: Come back to the-
Delwath: Oh, come back to the main room?
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Uh, how did I do...
DM: Okay, so.
Seeker: I, I was gonna go pee if something's about to happen.
DM: Okay, go ahead. Yes.
Seeker: Okay, thank you. [laughs]
Unknown: Take a break.
Kenzo: And I'm gonna plug in my computer.
DM: Hey, that's pretty good, Schwartz.
Wellby: Eh, sort of.
DM: It's getting your shirt a little bit too, but...
Wellby: Well, I'm naturally stealthy.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: There you go.
Kenzo: Am I, uh... Is this a mesa?
Kenzo: Is this, like, kinda what we're looking at, more or maybe?
DM: Yeah, that's pre- that's, that's pretty good.
DM: I mean, think like, you know, combination of Arizona and Texas Hill Country.
Kenzo: All right. That's not bad.
DM: So that's pretty good.
Seeker: That,
DM: that effect is a little bit strange, Schwartz, because some of the books are bleeding through.
DM: All right, cool.
Unknown: Uh,
DM: hey, Kong, are you on Roll20?
Kenzo: Ooh, let me get on there.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: So-
Kenzo: Um, I should be. The trick is...
Kenzo: Oh, I need to join Taelgar's-
Kenzo: Oh, wow. Look at that.
Kenzo: There's like a whole map and everything.
Kenzo: Ha ha ha.
Delwath: Fancy way to start.
Seeker: This is cool.
Seeker: Oh, but we're not on the map, but that's okay.
Seeker: Oh, wait. There are people on the map.
Delwath: Are we supposed to be on the map?
Seeker: I see.
Unknown: Uh.
DM: Yep.
Unknown: It's-
Wellby: Oh, shit.
DM: So this is-
Kenzo: Okay.
Kenzo: That's your apartment.
Unknown: Got it.
DM: This is the caravanserai.
Seeker: Uh...
Seeker: Schwartz, are you rigging a green screen?
Seeker: Yes.
Delwath: Yeah, he is.
Seeker: [laughs] I love it.
Seeker: Dedication.
Delwath: That is dedication.
DM: Okay, let's put on some villagers here.
Kenzo: [blows raspberry] Ooh, maybe I, I'm gonna try to do two laptops.
DM: See if this is gonna work.
Kenzo: I had a second one that...
Delwath: Hey, success.
Wellby: Virtual background.
Seeker: Oh, that looks nice, man.
Unknown: Yeah?
DM: Hot stuff.
Wellby: All right. I gotta find a desert-y-er one.
DM: Oh, that's awesome.
DM: That works perfectly.
DM: Okay, so,
Unknown: um,
DM: as you all come running out of your respective buildings and down the, uh, slash down the hill into town, um, you see before
Seeker: you...
Seeker: Let's see. Stop here.
DM: Um.
DM: Oh, this...
Seeker: Annoying.
Seeker: Sorry, guys. I should've set this up.
Kenzo: Yeah, you're good, man.
Kenzo: Oh, wow. All right, cool.
Kenzo: Nice.
Kenzo: I'm doing two laptops. I'm trying this out right here.
Kenzo: So I've got Zoom on this thing, and then I've got a Roll20-
Kenzo: Yeah
Seeker: ... over here.
Kenzo: Oh, this actually makes this way better.
Kenzo: Now it's like I've got you guys up on the Zoom here, and then I've got the Roll20 over here, so it's like all, all open at the same time.
Unknown: Nice. Nice.
Seeker: That's pretty.
Delwath: I should try that.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: This is actually working out pretty nicely.
Kenzo: Oh, yeah.
Kenzo: Progress.
Seeker: I guess I could try to put things more side by side.
Unknown: I have a-
Seeker: But then they're smaller
Wellby: ... I have a moni- a second monitor up there.
Wellby: If I keep staring into space, that's what I'm...
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Oh. My monitor's up in the office.
Unknown: Hmm.
Seeker: Or I could just use the TV up above the mantel.
Kenzo: We're just... We'll, we'll continue optimizing this as we, uh-
DM: Yeah. So as you look, l- as you all look down, running out of the, um, your respective
DM: inns and homes and,
DM: uh, down the hill,
DM: um, you see in front of you...
DM: Uh, and I'll... And as soon as we, as soon as I describe the scene, uh, I'll let you all describe yourselves, and then you can say what you're doing.
DM: Um, you see in front of you, uh, a scene of imminent carnage, as two enormous creatures, um, hyena
DM: in form, but more than twice as big as any hyena you've seen, blood dripping off of their mouths, um, snarling in fury, are
DM: looking around at villagers, um, who are beginning to scatter, as if trying to select their victims.
DM: Um, looking, uh, towards the outskirts of town, you see, coming down the hill...
DM: Take it away, Kong.
Unknown: Ooh.
Kenzo: Coming down the hill, you see a, um, a plainly dressed man, um, wearing-
Unknown: Kong
Kenzo: ... oh, can you hear me?
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Sounds good.
Kenzo: Okay. You see a, a plainly dressed figure, um, hooded, a simple tunic.
Kenzo: A very, very, um, non, nondescript
Kenzo: blend.
Kenzo: [laughs] But carrying a, carrying a, um, a staff, and, um, looking very alarmed at, at the scene unfolding.
Kenzo: Um, about 6' tall, athletic looking, um, but, but hard to get a look at his face right now because he's, he's hooded, despite...
Kenzo: And it's, uh, it... What's the temperature right now?
Kenzo: And what's the, what's the time of day again?
DM: So it's morning.
DM: It would be early enough that it's not the middle of the blazing heat.
DM: It's, but it's, it's still, I think it's still ear, you know, early spring, right?
DM: So, you know, maybe
DM: mid-April, something like that.
DM: So it's not the heat of the summer yet.
Kenzo: Okay. So despite, despite the warm temperature, still, still, um, uh, uh, still hooded, and, um, can't get a great look at his face.
Kenzo: But, um, looking at, looking at him, he looks like he's been around and then knows, knows his way around a fight.
Kenzo: Um, and he's got his staff pulled out,
Kenzo: um, a quarter staff, and looks ready to, uh,
Kenzo: potentially spring into action if needed.
DM: Looking, looking across-
Delwath: Sorry, where is this person?
Delwath: This fig- the...
Delwath: Up here?
Kenzo: Yep, way up there.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Coming down the hill.
Delwath: It's a tall human with a staff.
Seeker: Okay.
DM: Yeah. Uh, looking across, running down the steps, um, of one of these, uh, small, um, baked mud houses,
DM: you see
Unknown: Mike.
Delwath: Um, so, uh, Alf, um,
Delwath: sort of medium build, um,
Unknown: uh,
Delwath: wearing... This was just the morning?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Would I have had ti- like, how...
Delwath: Would I have put my, would I have had time to put my armor on?
DM: You would have a few minutes while-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... people were like, if you had someone run-
Delwath: Like somebody who's young from Halpoon who's clear there was some attack going on.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Okay. So, um, so he's, um,
Delwath: medium build, um, uh,
Delwath: pale silver sort of, um, relatively short cropped hair.
Delwath: His skin is like a burnished copper color.
Delwath: Um, and his eyes are sort of flashing golden.
Delwath: Uh, definitely a distinctive appearance.
Delwath: Um, he's carrying a long sword in one hand, and, um, has his other hand sort of raised, rushing down the steps with, like, a small, um, green
Delwath: gem or crystal or something.
Delwath: Um, and then he's wearing a suit of, uh, chain mail.
Delwath: Sort of comes rushing up pr- looking prepared for, for a fight of some kind.
DM: And across the way, emerging from the courtyard of the caravanserai, you see
DM: one of you, Schwartz and Eric.
DM: Eric, why don't you go first?
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um, a
Seeker: great big, uh, beard appears first, uh, blonde braided beard, uh, proceeding, um, a scurrying, uh, scholarly looking dwarf
Seeker: who's, um, working on getting his, uh, short sword out of its sheath,
Seeker: uh, while with the other hand, um, consulting a small notebook, uh, and-
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: ... peering around, uh, through his spectacles.
DM: And next to him, you see...
Wellby: Next to him is a halfling also loosening his short sword in the sheath, uh, in a green coat and a wide brimmed hat.
Wellby: Uh, s- uh, sort of quick moving, uh, uh, diminutive figure, uh, deeply tanned,
Unknown: uh,
Wellby: starting to move faster towards the danger.
DM: Okay. So,
DM: hold on, I... Kong just emailed me an image, so I gotta,
Unknown: uh,
Seeker: fix that.
DM: Okay. So where were you? Right about there.
DM: So, and, um, does everybody have the, um,
DM: like, the Beyond 20 setup so we can do, um, transfer roles and stuff?
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Okay. So,
DM: roll initiative.
Seeker: Oh, man, I thought this was, like, the s- the story part with the subtlety and the...
Seeker: Oh, man.
Delwath: You don't have the turn tracker up though, Tim.
DM: Uh, oh, wait, hold on. I gotta...
DM: I'll add you guys, you gotta get it up.
Wellby: My very first roll is a natural one.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Aw.
Seeker: I think you may have tripped.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Okay. So, um,
DM: how do I,
Unknown: uh-
Wellby: Oh, this thing's a little hard to read here
DM: And
DM: so who else? We need, um...
DM: Why are there two of me?
DM: It's okay.
DM: Are there two of you?
Delwath: That's fine.
DM: If you scroll down to-
DM: Oh, literally I accidentally, I accidentally added you to the turn order twice.
Seeker: Oh, yeah, it's...
Seeker: Did my roll come in?
DM: Yep.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Uh,
DM: okay, so...
Kenzo: Oh, wait, I need to...
DM: Okay, you're Wellby Goodbarrel is four and...
DM: Oh, wait, Seeker, 16.
DM: Okay. So I still need, um...
DM: Kong, I still need a roll for you.
Unknown: Kong?
Seeker: He's doing it.
Seeker: He's doing dance.
Seeker: Oh, he's muted.
Seeker: You're muted. [laughs]
DM: I know, I don't...
Unknown: Better?
DM: Tim, you muted him.
DM: No, when I hit unmute all,
DM: he immediately re-mutes.
Seeker: Wait, Kong, use sign language to tell us
Seeker: what we need to do.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Hold on.
DM: One word.
Wellby: It's two.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: E- every time I try and unmute you...
Delwath: One word, one word: his mic, his headset is dead.
Seeker: Oh, no.
DM: He's dead.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: He's un-
Seeker: It got dark really fast.
Seeker: I don't know
DM: what's happening.
Delwath: We're all waiting in suspense.
DM: Oh, the second
Kenzo: Okay. Can you hear me?
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: Yes. Oh, God, I don't know what the fuck happened.
Kenzo: That was really weird. All right. [laughs] Sorry about that.
DM: Oh, okay.
DM: Okay. [laughs] So initiate.
Kenzo: Having some weird technical things going on.
Kenzo: But anyways, all right. So let me, let me try to...
Kenzo: I, I need to make sure my, um, my D&D Beyond is linked to the, the thing.
Kenzo: Um-
DM: No, it should be. I just changed the name, so it should be linked.
Kenzo: Okay, good.
Unknown: Sweet.
Kenzo: So let me, um...
Kenzo: Hold on. Sorry, I'm just, uh, working out a kink over here.
Kenzo: Okay. So if I now go to,
Kenzo: um...
Kenzo: Sorry, y'all.
Seeker: It's all good.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Give me, give me a moment to orient here.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: how do I get back into the campaign
Kenzo: from the main D&D Beyond page?
Kenzo: Oh, here it is. Okay. Sorry.
Kenzo: Okay.
Kenzo: Okay, so now I'm in.
Kenzo: It says, "No VTT found that matches your setting."
Kenzo: I wonder what that means.
Kenzo: Um-
Wellby: I think it means that you don't have Roll20 up at the same time.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You need them both in the same...
DM: Yep.
Unknown: Um.
Kenzo: I'm there.
Kenzo: So I'm in Roll20.
Kenzo: I see Krunk.
Unknown: Uh-
Seeker: Oh.
DM: Oh, maybe you're in the wrong Roll20.
DM: Are you, are you on the Taelgar Revisited or Hack and Slash?
Kenzo: Yeah. Okay, let me do this. So I think I was just having a little problem with that.
Kenzo: Okay, so now I'm loaded in here.
Kenzo: Okay.
Kenzo: Server uplink. I'm, think I'm in.
Kenzo: Okay. So I think I'm in.
Kenzo: So now
Unknown: how do I-
DM: Just click on the...
Unknown: On your-
Kenzo: Where is he?
DM: Right in the front and center of your character sheet, like next to armor class, there's initiate.
Kenzo: I see it. Okay, there it is.
Kenzo: Okay, great, great, great.
Kenzo: Beyond20.
Kenzo: Good roll.
DM: There you go.
Kenzo: Yes. Okay. Thank you. Sorry about that, y'all.
Unknown: No problem.
Unknown: Perfect.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: Okay, great, great, great.
DM: Okay, so this, you see the scene before you as these two massive creatures start looking around, growling, and this commoner, this, the villagers who are sort of out on their
DM: early morning errands are just scattering.
Seeker: One, two,
DM: three, four, five, six. Just running as far as they can, as this one now charges.
DM: One sees this closest, um, villager and,
Unknown: uh,
DM: lunges to, to bite for it, and just
DM: rips this, um, young man to shreds with its teeth.
Seeker: This is not so good.
DM: Okay, Delwath.
DM: All right.
Delwath: Oops, that's not the direction I'm going.
Seeker: Ah, what is it doing?
Delwath: Something's going weird here.
Kenzo: One...
Delwath: Uh, sorry, I'm having technical troubles.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: When I try to move, it, the map scrolls in the other direction.
DM: Oh. Yeah. Um, just, just, uh, relo- just, like, uh, refresh the page.
DM: That's happened to me before.
Unknown: It'll just take a few-
Delwath: It's like, I'm not trying to run away.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Or you can just, like-
DM: ... point where you wanna move.
Delwath: One, two, three, four.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: So...
Kenzo: Uh, that's not there.
DM: You could get there if you wanted to.
Delwath: Well, I don't wanna get in combat range right now.
Delwath: I just don't want it to kill other things.
Delwath: What is this that's an awning?
DM: That's an awning. You can go under that.
Delwath: Let's see. One, two, three, four, five.
DM: I'll go here.
DM: And miss.
DM: That misses, sadly.
Seeker: What did you attack with?
Delwath: I, I blasted. Uh, you would see a str- beam of crackling energy streak from the, my hand that's holding the gem towards the creature.
Seeker: Oof. [laughs] My eyes kind of-
Unknown: These are high-
Seeker: My eyes kind of perk up at the, at the gem.
Seeker: I'm pretty curious about that. We'll have to explore that later on.
Unknown: Um,
DM: so, uh,
DM: phew. Um.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: This is fine. Uh, I'm thinking about trying to, um, trip one of these things into a hole,
Seeker: but how large is it, actually?
Seeker: Like-
DM: It's, like, 10 feet across.
Delwath: 10 feet across.
DM: They're big. They're hu- I mean, they're, they're bigger than a person.
Unknown: And-
DM: They don't fill this entire square, but, you know, they are much larger than...
DM: Even though they look sort of hyena-ish, they're much larger than a typical hyena.
DM: They're not, like, dog sized.
DM: They're like elephant si- Well, they're not quite elephant sized, but-
DM: Dog, horse
DM: ... horse size at least.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Um, um, oh, uh, hyenas famously, um, are, um, they, they will chuckle
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Is that true?
Delwath: I like your joke.
Delwath: It's true.
Delwath: They, they last-
Kenzo: I like where you're going with this right now.
Unknown: Um,
DM: and um-
DM: So I, I believe, though, you might just...
DM: I, I, I think I know what you're going for.
DM: Just look at the...
DM: Read the spell before you cast it,
DM: if I, if I know what you're going for.
Unknown: I believe.
Seeker: A creature with an intelligence score of four or less is not affected.
Seeker: Um, incapacitated, that's a good word here.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: They probably have a low intelligence score, though.
Seeker: Hmm. I don't have a good sense of, like, what a four intelligence is.
Seeker: Is that...
DM: A four is, like-
Delwath: Four is, like, a
Delwath: chimpanzee probably.
DM: Like, a chimpanzee is, like, a four.
Seeker: Oh, so they're... It's probably below that.
Seeker: Damn.
DM: A chimpanzee might be a five.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: An ape is a six according to D&D.
Seeker: Right. Um,
Seeker: okay. Sorry this is a little slow here.
Seeker: I'm just getting familiar [laughs] with my actual-
DM: That's fine
Kenzo: ... uh, spell-based abilities.
Seeker: Dude, it's all good. It's all good.
Unknown: Um.
Kenzo: David, you should, uh... I, I don't know if you've got a little light music to play in the background, too.
DM: Oh, I... Yeah, I do. It's just too quiet.
DM: Tell me if that's too loud.
Kenzo: I can't hear anything at all.
DM: Can't hear anything.
DM: Oh, I'm not sharing my music.
Seeker: Ha ha ha.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: I thought I was being all clever.
Unknown: [Instrumental music]
Kenzo: Nice.
DM: You got it now?
Delwath: We can hear now.
Wellby: Can you share... Can you share your music through Roll20, and then we can adjust the music volume separately?
DM: No, you can't. I can only share it through Zoom.
Delwath: There's a jukebox in Roll-
DM: Roll20 has a jukebox, but it's not connected to Spotify, so you can basically just play sound-
Unknown: Oh
DM: ... which is sort of useless.
Delwath: That's too bad.
DM: Yeah, I know. It's, like, one of the most requested Roll20 features, but it has not been implemented yet,
DM: sadly.
Seeker: So is this, um, the hyena that's, that's closest to me, is it lunging in a particular direction that I could anticipate and perhaps run over and use my,
Unknown: um,
Seeker: mold earth and stone ability to, like,
Seeker: uh, make a hole for it to trip into?
DM: Like, just a aiming for the-
DM: Oh, this one here that's right here?
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: It just, like, grabbed this thing, this, uh, young man,
DM: th- threw him to the ground and is now kind of looking around.
Seeker: Hmm.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: oh, I can make, I can make the ground difficult terrain so it's harder for thing, for the thing to move.
Seeker: I'm gonna do that. So I...
Seeker: The range is 30 feet, so I'm gonna have to, like, run over to get close enough to him, and I'm...
Seeker: My move is 25.
Seeker: Um.
DM: That's five squares.
Unknown: That's five squares.
Delwath: So one, two, three, four, five.
DM: One, two, three, four, five.
Seeker: And so I have to be within six.
Seeker: One to six.
Kenzo: You're, like, you're, like...
Delwath: You could make it difficult terrain right in front of him.
Seeker: Hmm.
Seeker: I'm, I'm just like, "Am I gonna run towards the freaking guy?"
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: That's a good question.
Delwath: I'm very curious as to the answer.
Seeker: Um. You also,
DM: you have, you have a crossbow, remember.
Seeker: Actually, I completely forgot about that.
Seeker: Um.
Kenzo: If you're all chatting, you can stop, by the way,
Unknown: in the Zoom.
Seeker: How does that even work?
Seeker: Can I just, like, s- shoot with the crossbow?
DM: Okay. Yeah.
Seeker: Okay, I'm gonna do that.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Where'd the...
Seeker: I rolled a six.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: No, you rolled a three.
Seeker: I rolled a three.
Delwath: You gotta pl- We're rolling really badly here.
Seeker: All right. So I shoot a crossbow bolt somewhere off into the distance.
DM: It goes flying off into the distance.
Kenzo: Kenzo, you're up.
Seeker: Wow, what a turn I just took. Thanks, everybody.
Kenzo: Can I, uh, get close enough to fight this h- hyena guy?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Yeah, you can get right there.
Kenzo: All right. So I, uh, you see this, this, this, uh, kind of, uh, this hooded figure with a, you know, athletic-looking figure with a, with a, a quarterstaff,
Kenzo: uh, rush over to the, the nearest h- hyena out in this clearing, and he strikes at him with his staff.
Kenzo: And
Seeker: see.
DM: That hits.
Delwath: Nice. Nice.
Delwath: Good job.
Kenzo: Slashes, slashes at the hyena.
Kenzo: So, so what does this mean damage-wise?
Unknown: Four.
Seeker: Six damage.
DM: Six, six damage.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: And then, uh, you can also follow up with a, um...
DM: Uh, you can use your bonus action to make a second unarmed strike.
Kenzo: Ooh, I will do that.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: I will do that.
Kenzo: Okay. So...
Unknown: [grunts]
DM: So that's an unarmed strike, not your...
DM: Yeah. That hits.
Kenzo: Nice.
DM: Another six points of damage.
Kenzo: So, so, so witnessing this from where you are all, all, from your different positions, you see just with, with just incredible just, um, skill and dexterity, you
Kenzo: know, slap, slap the head of, the head of the hyena with a, with a staff, and then with bare hands, like, taking the elbow and just hitting it again in a just really quick succession,
Kenzo: um, with, with
Kenzo: remarkable skill.
Seeker: Damn.
DM: That's gonna give some time for-
Seeker: It is a, a big, nasty thing to punch in the face like that.
DM: Uh, this actually is gonna run towards the elf.
DM: Behind... This, this, um, young woman is gonna hide behind the elf.
DM: This one also is gonna run one, two, three, four, five, six.
DM: Dashing to go one, two, three, four,
DM: five, six.
DM: And then this one is dead.
DM: Okay, this... So as you, as this, um,
DM: you know, man runs down and whack, whack, uh, smashes the zahina, uh, this large hyena-like creature, it turns around
DM: and looks at you, Kenzo, its eyes sort of almost glowing red as it-
Unknown: Oh
DM: ... lunges forward with you, with your j-
Unknown: Fair
DM: ... with its jaw dripping at you as you just-
DM: Oh, geez
DM: ... sidestep it gracefully, and the, it, its entire head just goes four inches above your shoulder that is no longer there
DM: as it misses.
Kenzo: [laughs] Yes.
Unknown: Good job.
DM: This one's running.
Kenzo: Why, why do these monsters all have to have glowing red eyes, Tim?
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Well, it's not-
Unknown: They, they-
DM: Its eyes aren't actually glowing red.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: It's just, you know, Tim's narrative trope.
Kenzo: Exactly.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Um, there's like blood dripping off his jaw, and it looks angry.
DM: It's not that his eyes are glowing red.
Kenzo: It's that it looks...
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Okay, this... So, um, this woman here is gonna take four, five...
DM: Four... One, two, three, four, five steps back and then raises her hand and makes a motion, and as nothing happens,
DM: she looks slightly, um,
DM: shocked and kind of taken aback by this whole scene.
Kenzo: Well, you know her.
Delwath: Do I know who that is?
DM: Uh, you've seen her around town.
DM: Um, she's a, um,
DM: she's a acolyte at the temple.
DM: She's a, she's a...
DM: Yeah, I'm gonna, I'm gonna send you a description.
Delwath: At least temporarily.
Kenzo: Yes. [laughs]
Delwath: Well, while you're doing that, it's Schwartz's turn.
DM: Yes, Schwartz, your turn. Sorry, I thought I said that.
Delwath: So, uh,
Wellby: I've been hanging around the town for a couple of weeks now.
Wellby: I did not come out this morning with armor or ranged weapons or anything.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: So I got my...
Wellby: [laughs] I thought it was just gonna be another boring day.
Unknown: Um,
Wellby: I'm gonna move towards the elf, and I'm sort of thinking of, um, if, uh, this guy...
Wellby: I don't know. Uh, hmm, uh, that's not visible.
Wellby: If the guy who just got eaten, um, is safe, maybe next round I'll try and stabilize him or something.
Wellby: Um, but I'll go one-
Delwath: This guy?
Kenzo: ... two. Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, is he alive, Tim?
Delwath: I got the impression his head was, like, physically separated from his body.
DM: Uh, no, he's, like, failing death saves.
Unknown: Ah, okay.
DM: As the giant, gi- giant bloody streak ripped out of his shoulder as he was tossed to the ground, but no, it's not, like, insta-kill.
Wellby: All right. Uh, I think...
Wellby: So I can get that far, and then I'm gonna move for my action.
Wellby: So here's another one, two, three,
Delwath: uh, four, five.
Wellby: [laughs] I'm sort of heading elf-ward.
Wellby: Or wait, yeah, that's the elf.
Wellby: Yep, that's me.
Seeker: Yeah, this is the elf here.
DM: Okay, this one is also gonna scatter.
Seeker: One, two, three, four, five.
DM: Uh, okay, this one is gonna keep running.
DM: Um, this one is gonna look around, and the giant hand now is gonna charge towards this woman.
Seeker: Oh, come on.
DM: And,
DM: uh,
DM: hit her, like, scratching a deep gash, um,
DM: uh, on her arm as she, like, tries to dodge out of the way, and she goes down to one knee, badly wounded but not dead.
DM: Delwath.
Delwath: All right, I am going to...
Delwath: Let me just... Da, da, da.
Delwath: I'm going to blast it again.
DM: Oh, that's better.
Unknown: Bet.
Kenzo: And then
Seeker: close with it.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: And try and, I mean,
Delwath: try and look threatening, and, um,
Delwath: you know, scare it a bit, if possible.
DM: As your, as your, uh, blast of magical energy, um,
DM: shoots out of your hand and, and hits it, it kind of,
DM: rrr, like, snarls and looks around, and sees you running towards it.
DM: Okay, Seeker, you're up.
Seeker: Um, I'm gonna use, uh,
DM: minor illusion
Seeker: to, um, as I wave my hands in the air, the, uh, illusion of a, um,
Seeker: a limping, uh, but otherwise plump and delicious antelope appears-
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: ... within range of sight of the giant hyena.
Kenzo: Yes.
DM: Um-
DM: Well, well, that might be a little complicated for, for, for minor illusion, but let me just look.
Delwath: No, you can, you can make any...
Delwath: It just doesn't have smell or sound.
Seeker: Can't make a sound, yeah.
DM: It, it'd have to be... It must... It'd have to f- fit in...
DM: So it'd have to be a small antelope.
DM: It'd have to fit in a five-foot space.
Seeker: Oh, it's a delicious tender, uh, uh-
DM: But it's a tender baby antelope
Seeker: ... baby antelope. [laughs] Yes, precisely.
Seeker: The range is 30 feet, so I have to position it somewhere, like, like, here-ish, I guess.
Unknown: Oh, wait.
DM: Yeah, you could, you could put it right there.
Seeker: Okay, yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Great. So there's a, there's like a limping baby antelope right there.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs] Kenzo, you're up.
Kenzo: All right.
Kenzo: Kenzo whips back again with his quarterstaff,
Kenzo: striking downwards, and...
DM: That hits.
Delwath: Nice.
Kenzo: Yes.
DM: Ooh, that's a lot of damage.
Kenzo: Again, strikes him on the back of the head, and then wheeling around with just his bare hands, strikes again.
DM: That hits.
Kenzo: Dude, I'm fucking this thing up.
Kenzo: Yes.
DM: Yeah, you are.
Unknown: The reason I-
Unknown: It's like...
Delwath: It's, so as you're...
DM: With this, like, second, um, flurry of strikes, it's, you know, it's, it's limping.
DM: Like, your second staff hit whacks it on the, on the, you know, the front leg and it like, "Ugh," like growls a bit, and then you bring your fist straight into
DM: its jaw and it staggers back slightly.
DM: Like, pretty badly knocked off its, off its course, um, by these-
Unknown: Sweet
DM: ... two rounds of, like, very solid blows.
Kenzo: Sweet. So, you know, again, if you're just kind of casually, like, watching from afar, it's like pretty proficient, badass, like, you know, flur- flurry of, of, uh, of strikes and blows,
Kenzo: effectively mo- uh, immobilizing this, this hyena.
DM: Okay, so this, this commoner is now, like, bleeding out.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: You probably have one round to save him before his, he's expired.
DM: Okay, so the giant hyena now, w- on his last legs,
DM: is going to, uh...
DM: What's your armor class?
Kenzo: I think 15.
Unknown: Is that right?
Kenzo: Oh, 16.
DM: Okay, so it just barely hits as you, like, dodge mostly out of the way, and it's, like, blood coming off of its mouth, like, from its, where you got...
DM: You know, where it got whacked, for six points of damage-
Kenzo: Damn
DM: ... as you just can't quite get out of the way fast enough.
DM: Oh, shit.
Kenzo: Fuck me up. [laughs] Okay.
DM: Okay, this one now runs off the map.
DM: Okay, so,
Unknown: um,
Unknown: this,
Unknown: uh,
Kenzo: woman now is gonna,
DM: um, raise her hands again and, like, try and reach out and strike this creature with a divine blow, and again,
DM: nothing happens, and she's looking around now kind of scared a bit at the situation.
DM: Wellby, you're up.
Kenzo: Uh, I'm gonna go
Wellby: here and try and stabilize that guy.
DM: Okay. Uh, make a medicine check.
DM: That... There's [laughs] there's your natural 20.
DM: Okay, he's stable.
Seeker: Wow.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: Now still unconscious, but not dying.
DM: Uh, this one's gonna run off the map.
DM: Okay, so this one's gonna run off around the corner.
DM: Okay, so this hyena now is, like, looking in, sort of in confusion, not sure what to do between the, the antelope that just appeared, sort of
DM: confusing it, and, you know, tempting it, and this
DM: creature behind it that just struck it with some unknown force that riled it up.
DM: And it, in its confusion, first attempts to bite
DM: at the creature, at the elf,
DM: um, which hits for seven points of damage.
Kenzo: All right, hold on.
Unknown: Seven.
DM: Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Kenzo: Okay.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Just waiting for that.
Kenzo: Um-
DM: Dex
Unknown: ... oh.
Kenzo: Um-
Overlap: See how it's a dex save
Delwath: ... I will, um, when it strikes, I'll point at it and a fl- and a, um, flame springs up all around it.
Delwath: Um, like it's engulfed in just these dark, black flames.
DM: So as this happens, it's like,
Delwath: can't decide if it wants-
Delwath: How much damage did you say it was?
DM: Uh, seven.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: And our... There's, like, uncertain as to which way to go.
DM: And as it rips into you, and then this, this black shadowy flame strikes around it, it decides the antelope looks like better prey, and then
Seeker: runs...
DM: Where is the antelope again?
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: It's, like, here, right?
Wellby: Or, like, roughly-
Seeker: Yeah.
Kenzo: One's, one's there, and,
DM: uh, leaps towards the antelope, giving you, Delwath, an attack of opportunity.
Delwath: No, I can't. I used my reaction.
DM: Oh, you used your reaction already.
Seeker: Okay.
DM: Uh, the a- the acolyte-
Delwath: The hellish rebuke was a reaction
Unknown: ... okay.
Seeker: Um,
DM: he will
DM: attempt... Um, the acolyte, as it's running away, just, um, attempts to, uh, slice at it with a dagger, but can't get through its hide.
DM: Um, and as it charges up towards the antelope, it, like, runs through the antelope and now is, like, even more angry than it was before, and like just lets this enormous-
Unknown: This is great
DM: ... bellow, looking around, just utterly confused by this, like, black flame coming out of nowhere,
DM: an antelope that disappeared.
DM: This, this beast seems to not know what to do at this point.
DM: Uh, Delwath, you're up.
Kenzo: Yes.
DM: That hits.
Delwath: So another crackling blast of energy comes flying out from Della's hand, and hits the creature again.
DM: And with that, it, like, staggers, um, not dead, but nearly so.
DM: Um, again, sort of howling in frustration more than
DM: fear or anything else.
DM: Uh, Seeker of Highkeep, you're up.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: so now it's close enough for me to, um, use mold earth to, um,
Seeker: uh, instantaneously excavate a five-foot cube of the ground and deposit it five feet away.
Seeker: So I'll try to, like,
DM: uh, just basically-
DM: Under it or, or something, or in front of it?
Seeker: ... um, remove what it's standing on under its front paws and move it between-
Unknown: Right
Seeker: ... the hyena and me so that there's a little-
DM: [laughs] Okay
Seeker: ... earth mound [laughs] and moat.
DM: Awesome. Uh, so it sort of falls...
DM: It'll, it... As you do this, it falls prone, basically, um,
DM: slipping on the ground as the earth disappears below it.
DM: Um, and-
Seeker: I guess now, strictly speaking, the antelope is floating above this hole in the ground, too.
DM: Yes, and it's very confused because it thinks-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... that it's mounted on an antelope, and there's clearly no antelope there.
DM: Uh, Kenzo, you're up.
Kenzo: All right.
Kenzo: Kenzo whips back with his staff again, hoping for a finishing blow,
Kenzo: and he strikes down, and...
DM: And that just barely hits.
Kenzo: Mm.
DM: Knocking it to the ground
DM: as it whimpers and collapses at your feet, dead.
DM: Woof.
Unknown: Nice.
Unknown: [sighs]
Kenzo: But Kenzo, des- despite, despite being able to, uh, um, dispatch of the, the, the creature is, is...
Kenzo: You know, I'm, I'm, I'm really, like, doubled over and, and not looking so hot from the, the earlier strike from the hyena.
DM: Uh, do you wanna move?
DM: Oh, can I move?
Wellby: Yeah, you can still move.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: I... Yeah, I'm gonna go and just move myself by this, by, by the edge of the building.
Kenzo: How far can I move?
DM: Um, what is your...
DM: Six squares. Your speed's 30 feet.
DM: Okay. Three, four, yeah.
DM: So you can move to, like, here, easily.
Kenzo: Yeah, that's exactly where I'm gonna move. I'm gonna move to that corner and just kinda get out of the way a little bit, get into the shade, and try to collect myself.
DM: Okay, so all of the commoners now are
DM: fleeing.
DM: Um, this one is stable but not dead.
DM: Um, this one is dead.
DM: This one is dead.
Unknown: Um,
DM: uh, this, um, woman is gonna try one more time with a divine blast, um, and again, uh,
DM: nothing seems to happen.
DM: Um, Wellby, you're up.
Wellby: So with a glance around to assess the situation,
Wellby: uh, and a slight look of surprise that someone was able to take out a hyena by whacking it with a stick and slapping it, um.
Wellby: [laughs] That is pretty impressive.
Wellby: I, uh, glance over, uh, and try and make eye contact with the other combatants as best I can.
Wellby: Um, and actually, I'll look to the elf, and, uh, elf guy who I haven't met yet, you'll
Wellby: hear a voice inside your head, silently, but inside your head saying, uh, "Well, cover me."
Wellby: [laughs] I'm gonna run over and, uh, take a swing at this guy.
Kenzo: Da-da.
Wellby: Uh, so, uh, sorry, hang on just a sec.
Unknown: Um...
DM: That hits.
Wellby: And as you-
Wellby: It will get... Don't get sneak attack damage, though.
DM: No, I know you don't get sneak attack.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: As you, as you stab it, you're...
DM: It's now, uh...
DM: Oh, you get it... No, you do get sneak attack because it's prone.
Unknown: Um-
Seeker: Yeah, it's, its face is in a hole [laughs]
DM: ... oh, now that it's prone, it actually can't stand it.
Wellby: Uh, should I roll again?
Delwath: Well, you hit. You don't have to roll again.
DM: Well, unless you can get a crit, you can, but, um, no.
DM: So you already hit, and you do get sneak attack 'cause you're at advantage.
DM: So with that, you manage to find a weakness in the, um, in its hide and just stab your sword, um, into this weak spot as it expires in front of you,
DM: um, taking advantage of its prone form to, uh, to find the one spot where you can, um, do the most damage.
Unknown: So,
DM: you look around.
DM: Two corpses of enormous hyenas at the, on the ground.
DM: Um, and now the shouts and noise of the village begins to come back as, um, you hear the cry, um,
DM: going around, um,
DM: not just the, like, "Help, help," but, you know, there's fighting.
DM: There's, there's beasts again.
Unknown: Um,
DM: the elf is there,
DM: and this sort of is echoing out from the scene as everybody seems to scatter and leave the four of you, um, standing on the battlefield
DM: looking at each other.
Delwath: Well, it... Does, uh, does the initiate woman scatter, too?
DM: Um- She, uh, she looks at you and she sort of recognizes you, and, um, yells out to you as she runs past, uh,
DM: "I'm going to get Candrosa."
Unknown: And then runs-
Kenzo: I'll just n- I'll nod.
Unknown: Oh, that's-
Kenzo: I, uh...
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: How far, how far away is she from me, Tim?
Kenzo: Or where, where is she on this map?
DM: Uh, she's, she's, like, running in this direction,
DM: sort of, yeah, down this passage...
DM: She's right here, and she's running towards-
Unknown: Okay
Seeker: ... like, this little road.
Kenzo: I see. She's, like, running?
DM: She, she said something to the elf.
DM: You heard her yell to the elf, "I'm going to get Candrosa."
Unknown: Uh-huh.
DM: And then she sort of goes off, not at a full sprint, but at a jog.
Kenzo: Okay. Okay.
Kenzo: Well, [laughs] I, uh, I just keep my eye on her and see what, what direction she's, she's running.
Unknown: She's going, like-
Kenzo: And does she, like, disappear down that, down that, that path?
DM: Disappears down-
Unknown: Yeah, okay
DM: ... this little, little alleyway.
Kenzo: Okay. Um-
DM: This is like... This is the tavern here, the caravansai with the courtyard and where sort of, uh, merchant stalls and stuff.
DM: This is, like, the edge of the village, basically.
Unknown: Got it.
DM: The oasis out of here.
DM: This isn't the oasis just yet.
Kenzo: How on... So, uh, just in D- in D&D parlance, like, how badly wounded am I?
Kenzo: Like, I'm pretty wounded relative to my total number of hit points.
Kenzo: Am I, like, staggering around or am I, like, cool?
Kenzo: Like, what, what is that, you know?
DM: I mean, if you're below half, it would probably mean-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... that you're noticeably wounded.
Kenzo: Okay.
Kenzo: Okay. In that case then, um, yeah, I just, I just sort of, uh, I, I'm definitely noticeably wounded, and start, start kind of limping forward, keeping my eye out at the, um, at where the,
Kenzo: where the, uh, woman is going, but also noticing, um, Mike, that your characters had an interaction.
Kenzo: So I, I just start kind of walking over slowly in your direction towards the elf.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Um, I'm gonna check on the, um, this guy, um,
Delwath: who's right next to me.
Delwath: Like, he's, he's stable, right?
DM: Yeah, he's stable.
DM: Okay.
DM: Did not, um-
Unknown: Um.
DM: You, you noticed in, during the fight that the
Kenzo: halfling-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... bandaged him up, and he seems to be in, um...
DM: Uh, I'm answering your message.
Unknown: Um.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Yes. These, uh-
Unknown: I-
DM: He seems to be, uh, not at any risk of dying in any way.
DM: He'll definitely have scars, but not
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Imminent death.
Delwath: All right. Um, I'll bring him under, just underneath the awning.
Delwath: Uh, is there somebody in the tea room or did everybody flee?
Unknown: Um,
DM: so yes, uh, pretty much everybody fled.
DM: Anybody who was-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... anywhere close, um, fled.
Delwath: But, I mean, did they flee out of the buildings?
Delwath: Like, was...
Delwath: If... I'm, I'm gonna, I'm gonna bring him into the tea room.
DM: Oh, you mean... Uh, so,
DM: um, a few customers ran out the back door.
DM: Um, but, uh, Badya, who, who you know-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
DM: ... who works there, um,
DM: uh, didn't, would not have run away.
DM: She's sort of hiding behind, um, some chairs and a table in the, in the tea room.
Delwath: All right. Well, I'll g- I'll go in, I'll bring him into the, into the tea...
Delwath: So you, so everybody sees the elf basically pick up,
Delwath: uh, this injured guy and run into this building.
Delwath: Or, or not run, but, but carry him into this building.
Wellby: I'll follow you in since this is the guy I stabilized.
Seeker: Nice, nice.
Delwath: Um, and I'll, I'll just get Badya's attention and, and just, um, find a place on the,
Delwath: um, you know, find a place in the tea room that I can, you know, put him down on a cushion or something and, and ask her to, to look after him, and you know, um,
Delwath: make sure he wakes up soon, and, and I'll be back.
Kenzo: Uh, but-
DM: Okay. So I-
Delwath: The, these, th- these, this attack was much worse than the last one, I'll tell her.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: And I wanna go see what's going on.
DM: She's probably surprised at that. Like, the first one was so bad already.
DM: Okay, so then you head out.
DM: So where... So everybody's, you're all now I guess kind of congregating near that fountain or something like that.
Delwath: Well, I wanna go look at the body.
Unknown: That's what I was-
Unknown: Well, we should all-
DM: ... I was about to do, yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, 'cause what are Eric and Schwartz doing?
Kenzo: I, I went, I was walking over to just, to...
Delwath: I was limping over to where, where, uh, where Mike's character was going.
Seeker: Okay.
Delwath: So I was kind of like, if the halfling's following me, that's great, but I'm kind of ignoring him to start.
Delwath: But I, like, I, like, glance in your direction, like,
Delwath: but not, like, being very welcoming or anything, but, and bringing the person into the...
Delwath: I mean, you can follow along, but then I'll go back out, and then I'll kind of look around at whoever's out.
Delwath: Uh, like, if everybody's standing around, um,
Delwath: you know, I'll walk over to the hyena, and anybody who's still around
Delwath: I'll turn to and say, "Well,"
Delwath: what's the name of the town again?
Kenzo: Um, Karawa.
Delwath: "Welcome to Karawa, travelers.
Delwath: This has happened more than you'd think."
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: are there likely to be more of these things?
Seeker: Uh, like, do we know which direction they came from?
DM: Can we look over there? [laughs]
DM: They, they came from the sort of
DM: east s- east, northeast.
DM: Um...
DM: Schwartz, what did your character do?
Wellby: So, I'm, I followed...
Wellby: When the elf grabbed my patient, very bad form to move a spine injury, first of all, elf.
Wellby: Uh, once I know that he's okay outside, [laughs] I'll go and, and see that that, that dude's stable inside and I'll come back out to gather with the rest of you again.
Seeker: Uh, and I'm, I'm crouching over the hyena corpse to see if I can learn anything about-
Delwath: Yeah, that's-
Seeker: It's... Whether it's, uh, got some magical-
Delwath: So is this, um-
Seeker: ... origin, or if it's just, like, a wild animal.
DM: Okay. Uh, so, um,
DM: Seeker make a investigation check.
DM: Dear, dear, dear.
DM: Investigation.
DM: Do, do, do.
DM: Okay. Is any... What's, uh...
DM: Just go around what everybody else is doing while, um, this dwarf is examining the-
Delwath: So actually, I will...
Delwath: First I wanna go investigate the body for a, just for a minute.
Delwath: Like, is it, is it natural?
Delwath: Does it seem to be, like, um,
Kenzo: a...
Delwath: Is it, like, naturally grown this big or does it seem to be enchanted or cursed or somehow magically whatever?
Unknown: Um,
DM: the... So I mean, you've heard rumor of
DM: beasts that grow this big out in the blasted plains.
DM: You, you all probably would've heard rumors of that, especially those of you who came from the east.
DM: So it's not... It wouldn't be, um,
Unknown: uh,
DM: it wouldn't be, like, something that was...
DM: It doesn't look like a normal creature that was, like, somebody cast Enlarge on or something like-
DM: Right. Right
DM: ... You wouldn't be, like, totally shocked to see something like...
DM: Although, somewhat shocked.
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: But you have heard stories about this.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: uh-
Delwath: And after I kind of poke at the body for a minute, um,
Delwath: uh, I'm gonna go,
Delwath: um, you s- see, uh, Delwath start to, like, take a few deep breaths and kind of, um,
Unknown: uh,
Delwath: close his eyes briefly and, um, start, like, concentrating on, you know, looking like he's concentrating on something.
DM: Okay. So that's what you're doing.
DM: Seeker's investigating the bodies.
DM: Wellby and Kenzo, what do you guys?
Kenzo: So we're the only two that aren't doing anything right now?
DM: Correct.
Kenzo: [laughs] But I, I, I...
Kenzo: I look over, I look over at the, at the halfling.
Kenzo: You're, you're a halfling, right?
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: I find, you know, I've, I've got my sta- I'm pretty badly wounded.
Kenzo: Like, the, the hyena, like, got me really good, like, kind of slashed me right across the, gashed me across the chest.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: So, like, I, I'm definitely not looking that hot.
Kenzo: So I, I kind of, you know, walk over to, to the halfling.
Kenzo: Like, walk over to you, uh, Schwartz, kind of grimacing, and I, and I look over.
Kenzo: Did I... Did... Would I have been, would I have been able to observe, um, uh, Schwartz's character healing or doing anything with the commoner?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I mean, you would've seen him-
Unknown: Oh, I-
DM: ... bandaged him up.
Kenzo: Right. Right. So I look over at you, Schwartz, and I, and I'm like, "And, uh-"
DM: Um, Eric and, and Kong, I both...
DM: I sent you messages on Slack, by the way.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Yeah, good.
DM: I mean, on chat.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Uh.
Wellby: So, uh,
Wellby: friend, that's an ugly looking one.
Wellby: I wish I could do something for you.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: About the best I can do is, uh, keep your remaining blood inside.
Kenzo: [laughs] I was just gonna say, I, I saw what you did there with that, uh,
Kenzo: that, that gentleman and I...
Kenzo: If you've got some skill, skill for me, I wouldn't mind.
Wellby: I, uh, I, I wish I could help, but, um-
Kenzo: Keeping the blood inside sounds pretty good right now.
Kenzo: I'm not, I'm not doing too well.
Kenzo: That, that was a pretty, that was a pretty rough attack.
Kenzo: I don't know what those things were, but-
DM: Um, h- hold on, hold on one sec.
DM: There's too many questions coming in.
DM: You guys keep talking.
DM: Mike, hold on one sec.
Kenzo: Yeah, sure.
Wellby: So, um, uh-
Kenzo: What's your name, traveler? What's your name, traveler?
DM: Uh, Wellby Goodbarrel.
Unknown: And you?
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Kenzo.
Wellby: Kenzo. Kenzo, you're good in a fight with that big stick of yours.
Kenzo: Uh, it serves me well from time to time, but I, I try not to get into tussles with, uh, beasts like that if I, if I can avoid it.
Unknown: Yeah, I, I-
Wellby: You ever seen these things before?
Wellby: I say generally to the group.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Are we all outside now? I thought, I thought Mike was still inside with the, uh-
Delwath: No, I'm outside in, like, a trance.
Kenzo: Oh, okay. Okay.
Seeker: I, I wanted to, uh, thank both of you fighters for dispatching these, uh, nasty, uh...
Seeker: Are they more like dogs or more like cats?
Seeker: I don't know. I've been poking around at its hide.
Seeker: Uh, I, I did notice, uh, that there's quite a bit of, uh, of dried blood all over, uh, the body of this, uh, this one at least over here that's got its head in the
Unknown: hole.
Seeker: Um, I, I wonder if it's, i- if it's been, um,
Seeker: in some, in some battles on the way over here.
Unknown: Oh.
Seeker: Uh, maybe even made some kills.
Seeker: Um, I wonder if we could follow them-
Unknown: [coughs]
Seeker: ... uh, over the desert to see where they came from.
Unknown: We could track it.
DM: What's your what?
Unknown: [coughs]
Unknown: What'd you say?
Wellby: Well, I started to say we could track it back, but then...
Wellby: Oh, uh, friends, you haven't been introduced yet.
Kenzo: I said, what, what, what's your name, traveler?
Seeker: Oh, I, I am, uh, Seeker of Highkeep.
DM: Your name is Seeker?
Unknown: That's right.
Delwath: Can you turn down the music a tiny bit, Tim?
Seeker: Yeah.
Unknown: Uh,
Seeker: nice to meet you all.
Unknown: Huh.
Kenzo: Is this, uh, Seeker your, your, your given name, or-
Seeker: Uh, I chose it,
Seeker: uh-
Unknown: Uh-
Seeker: At a moment of lucidity.
Wellby: Hmm, hmm.
Seeker: Uh, I don't know if you're familiar with, uh, dwarven culture, but we have a, uh, rite of passage, uh, ritual in adolescence.
Unknown: Uh,
Seeker: it's uh-
Unknown: Hmm
Unknown: ...
Seeker: it's quite an ordeal.
Seeker: I don't usually, uh,
DM: like to talk about it very much.
Kenzo: But, um,
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: I had a vision at that time, and, and now I, I, I journey, uh, uh, uh,
Seeker: seeking answers about a certain set of questions that I'm interested in, you might say.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: And I, I glance over at the elf.
Kenzo: Is he still in a trance?
Delwath: Well, he's looking around a little bit disturbed at the moment.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Like, like there's something invisible that he's trying to find or f- or see, but, but it doesn't look like it's like a sort of very
Delwath: concentrated searching around in the area around the hyenas, but not looking at anything visible.
Kenzo: Are you still, uh, are you still, like, in a trance, or are you kind of aware?
Delwath: No, no, no. Now he's like, he looks focused-
Unknown: All right
Delwath: ... but not in a particular trance.
Delwath: After about, after about a few, a minute of that, or, or while you guys are talking, after...
Delwath: Well, you could say something at the moment.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: He's like, right now he's looking around.
Kenzo: I, I, I would, I actually, uh, walk over to you, wherever you, if you're a few steps away, I just walk over.
Unknown: Yes.
Kenzo: And, uh, um, just sort of kind of motion cautiously to make sure you're not, you're not still, like...
Kenzo: You know, like I'm in, it's not, not interrupting anything.
Seeker: Right.
Kenzo: Sort of getting into your line of sight to see if you're there, if you're, you, you notice me, and sort of-
Delwath: So Delwath will look up.
DM: Yeah, he'll look up-
DM: Okay
Delwath: ... and sort of nod at you a bit and say, um,
Delwath: "Uh, apologies.
Delwath: This is a very, um,
Delwath: unexpected, although oddly not the first time it's happened here.
Delwath: And my housebility, uh, hos- hospitality to, uh,
Unknown: um,
Delwath: some, you
Delwath: very helpful warriors in this, in this battle has been, um, quite insufficient."
Delwath: And he sort of nods a bit, and, "Apologies for, for ignoring you.
DM: There's s-
Unknown: Uh
Delwath: ... something odd going on here, though."
Kenzo: All right. What's your name, traveler?
Delwath: Uh, Delwath.
Delwath: I've been here for s- for several months, actually.
Wellby: And this wasn't the first attack?
Kenzo: The third.
Seeker: Hmm. Is it always these, uh, hyena creatures?
Delwath: No, this is the f- this is the...
Delwath: Uh, hyenas, yes.
Delwath: Um, this size, no.
Seeker: Oh, they're normally smaller.
Delwath: Well, they're normally hyena-sized.
Unknown: Aha.
Seeker: Yeah, these ones look big enough you could put a saddle on.
Delwath: Yeah. And there's,
Delwath: there's something wrong with the magic here.
Seeker: Um, I perk up at this.
Seeker: [laughs] What do you mean about that?
Kenzo: Um,
DM: hold on a second.
Delwath: It, it's hard to expl- [laughs] it's hard to explain exactly.
Delwath: I can't quite see where it's coming from.
Kenzo: But there's a-
Unknown: Hmm
Delwath: ... there's like a, there's something distorted here.
Seeker: Distorted.
Kenzo: Delwath, do you know Candrosa?
Delwath: Uh, yeah. I've met her a few times.
Kenzo: Huh. A she.
Kenzo: Uh, him.
Unknown: Him.
Delwath: No, him, I think.
Delwath: Tim, I don't remember.
Delwath: Him or her.
Delwath: Uh, he. Candrosa-
Unknown: He, sorry.
Delwath: I don't have my little cheat sheet open.
Delwath: I'm also interested-
Delwath: I've met him a few times
Seeker: ... I'm also interested in meeting Candrosa.
Kenzo: Huh.
Seeker: Uh.
Kenzo: Apparently we have this in common, friend.
Unknown: Indeed.
Kenzo: Why do you seek Candrosa?
Seeker: Well, I came to this place because it's, uh, it's got all kinds of interesting features, actually.
Kenzo: Um-
Unknown: Uh
Seeker: ... if, if you, uh, look at the geology around us, um, uh, we're in this, uh, uh, desert plain, but obviously there's a sandstone, um, uh, mesa,
Seeker: uh, with, uh, quite beautiful grain and, and texture.
Seeker: But there's this, uh,
Seeker: ancient, uh, temple carved into it, uh, which is the site of, um,
Seeker: uh, convergence of, uh, these magical lines of power.
Seeker: Uh, which makes me wonder, um, uh, how that came to be, uh, and, uh, and what, uh, forces, uh, within and without this plane of existence might
Seeker: have, um, caused the convergence.
Delwath: Delwath is like you were starting to talk.
Delwath: Delwath is sort of clearly really much more focused on this strange, magical something than whatever you're saying.
Kenzo: When you say strange magical, magical something, you're talking about the hyena?
Delwath: Uh, no, the thing he mentioned.
Delwath: He's still looking around, trying, like, he's clearly interested in something that he sees in this, in this area.
Kenzo: Huh.
Delwath: This disturbance of the...
Unknown: Um.
Kenzo: Is Candrosa coming here?
Delwath: It wouldn't surprise me if he shows up, yeah.
Wellby: Who is that?
Seeker: Uh, Candrosa, I'm told, is, uh, in charge of the religious ceremonies, correct?
Kenzo: [laughs] Tim, uh, is there...
Kenzo: Do, uh... Actually, I'm, I'm still gashed up, right?
Unknown: So
Kenzo: I'm just, I'm just looking around.
Kenzo: I, is, is there a place to like sit down or, or like-
Delwath: Yeah, come here
Kenzo: ... rest?
Delwath: I, I'll, I'll suggest... Well, no, actually I'm still-
Kenzo: You're still in the, um-
Wellby: I'm, I'm still in the-
DM: There's a... I mean, looking around, yes, you would see, I mean, there's, like, under the awn- So there's this awning in front of this tearoom, and under the awning there would be a few chairs.
DM: Um, you know-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... there's like a table and a few chairs kind of set up-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... where people would've, have been, you know, sipping-
DM: ... their morning tea or something.
Kenzo: Um, there's also near the-
Unknown: I, I-
DM: You know, Vancer, yeah.
Kenzo: I, I grimace and just, uh, and just poi- I gesture at all of you.
Kenzo: I'm gonna go sit [laughs] as I grab my staff and start hobbling over.
Kenzo: I find, like, if there's like a...
Kenzo: Is there, is there like a, a table where there's some, like, food and, you know, somebody, like, was eating food and, like, had some drink and they, like, ran off, you know?
Unknown: Nice.
DM: Yeah, there's like a-
Kenzo: I find a table of that.
Kenzo: I find a table like that where there's like some, some, you know, half eaten food and like some drink or whatever, and I sit down [laughs] and start, I just start helping myself to some breakfast as I, as I'm
Kenzo: like, just like, kind of like keeled over on the staff, like still wounded, but, but, you know, just starting to eat something.
Unknown: Um, oh-
Kenzo: And I just start pointing at you guys and just like, "I, I gotta, I have to sit."
Kenzo: And then I, then I just hobble over.
Seeker: I join you at the table and, uh, and, um, pull out a little notebook and start, uh, sketching a, a star shaped diagram.
Unknown: All right.
Wellby: I grab a pot of tea and a tea cup off, off some other abandoned table and join you in a sip.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: So, so Seeker-
Delwath: Tim's typing something to me, and, and then I can come in.
DM: Yes, it's, it's slightly complex, so...
Kenzo: Seeker, you, uh...
Kenzo: Say, say again why you seek Candrosa.
Kenzo: Sorry, I, I'm, uh-
Unknown: So-
Kenzo: ... still trying to recover here a little bit.
Kenzo: This is pretty painful.
DM: Oh, yeah, take your time.
Seeker: Uh, your, your actions, uh, certainly saved some lives earlier.
Seeker: Uh, s- Candrosa is the, uh, so-called Speaker of Shakun.
Seeker: Uh, Shakun being the local, uh, uh, uh, mystery cult.
Seeker: Ooh.
Seeker: Uh, I've heard of them from afar.
Seeker: And, uh, I've come because, uh, they may have an understanding of, uh, kind of a connection point
Seeker: that, uh, exists in this place.
Seeker: Uh, are, are you familiar with the, uh, invisible micro- invisible magical, uh, lines of power that, uh, uh, form a, uh, web-like network across the surface of our world?
Wellby: I am.
Wellby: When you say, when you say familiar-
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: When, when-
Delwath: Just as you're saying that, the elf walks in.
Delwath: Okay. [laughs] I'm holding up a-
Delwath: And sort of perks up at that statement a bit, um, and sort of glances over.
Delwath: And then, um, he looks over at one of the, a younger woman who's like a bartender and stuff, and s- and, um, uh, you see him like
Delwath: whisper something to her.
Delwath: Or like to, you'd hear, if you were listening, he's saying like, "Bring us some fresh food."
Delwath: Um, and he comes in and he like s- sits, he goes to sit down and he like clears off the table, is like,
Delwath: "Let's, let's be civilized, folks.
Delwath: We could eat some fresh food."
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Oh, thanks. Uh, yeah, I appreciate that.
Unknown: Um-
Kenzo: Even, even more than the food, some bandaging would be, would be wonderful.
Delwath: I don't know if anybody has something here.
Kenzo: I'm, I'm still
Wellby: bloody.
Delwath: Yeah, I mean, Delwath like has blood coming out of his arm too.
Delwath: He just hasn't mentioned it so far.
Seeker: Oh, I can, um, I can speak a, a healing word, so to speak, to assist,
Seeker: uh, when I notice this.
Kenzo: [laughs] That would be marvelous, friend.
Seeker: Um, how do...
Seeker: Okay, how do I do that? Let's see.
Unknown: Um.
DM: Uh, if you cast, if you just click to cast the spell, it should-
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: Okay, so you get four, four points of, four health back.
Delwath: Everybody, or just, uh-
DM: No, just-
Delwath: Just, um, Kenzo?
Seeker: Just Kenzo.
Delwath: Squeaky wheel gets the grease.
Delwath: That's fair.
DM: So as you, um, as you're talking-
Seeker: I mean, we're sitting next to each other at a table, yeah.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Yeah. Well, no, I mean, Delwath took almost as much damage, he just hasn't complained about it.
Delwath: [laughs] Oh, I see.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: That's nice.
Kenzo: Friend, appreciated.
Seeker: Oh, my pleasure. My pleasure.
Delwath: So Delwath looks over at you and, and sort of a little quizzically says, "You're here seeking ley lines?"
Seeker: Yeah, yeah. Some call them ley lines.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: they're, they're part of a, uh, a larger, uh, system that my inquiry's focusing on.
Seeker: Um, uh, I'm very interested in, in interconnections be- uh, between things.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: uh, I don't know if you've, you've heard of the city of, uh, Darakan.
Seeker: It's very far to the north of here.
Seeker: It's a, it's a beautifully constructed, uh, one of the classics really, of dwarven architecture.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: and, uh, and my folks, my parents, were the
Seeker: principal architects.
Seeker: And, uh, from, from them I got a taste for
Seeker: studying and, and understanding the, the shape of things and how they're made and put together.
Seeker: Uh, but, but I'm also interested in, in the, the less material and those structures as well that are-
Seeker: The architecture, you might say, of the energy that binds us
Wellby: Is that the map you were looking at earlier?
Seeker: Uh, yeah, I was, I was sketching these so-called, uh, ley lines where, uh...
Seeker: You can see the, at the convergence point of this, this star.
Seeker: I think that that point is, um, somewhere inside of the, the temple over there in that sandstone, uh, mesa.
Seeker: Uh, and I, I should say, uh, I have some familiarity with, with rocks and stones, and there's-
DM: Oh, my God, everybody else stopped messaging me at the same time.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Oh, no.
DM: I'm still, like, four messages behind to Mike, so keep talking.
Seeker: Sorry.
Seeker: I'm not messaging Tim.
Seeker: There's something very odd, let's just say, about-
DM: I'll, I'll get you
Seeker: ... about the stone there,
Seeker: and I'm curious to find out more about that.
Unknown: Hm.
Wellby: I say, uh, I'm something of a mapmaker myself.
Seeker: It's-
Seeker: Oh, really?
Wellby: ... part of what brings me in this direction.
Wellby: There's so much blank on the map to the east of here.
Wellby: I've always been curious.
Seeker: Indeed, and the history of this region is, is quite strange as well, from what I'm told,
Seeker: uh, with respect to, um, sudden, rather cataclysmic change.
DM: This is something you all would have known.
DM: Like, 200 years ago, uh, this, like, the western coastal part of Dunmar just, like, rose up out of the ocean, and these mountain chains were created,
Unknown: um,
DM: were sort of pushed up. Some of them are older, but there are some very new parts of the mountain, and that completely changed the climate of Dunmar.
DM: It used to be much more fertile plains, but with the mountains rising up, it created a rain shadow effect and changed the climate to this mu- much more arid desert, and just
DM: had, like, a cataclysmic impact on all,
Unknown: um,
DM: all of the country.
DM: On top of, of course, Cha'mut killing everybody.
Unknown: Hm.
Kenzo: So, Wellby, you're here seeking maps?
Wellby: Yeah, tell me more.
Wellby: Well, uh,
Wellby: uh, I'm here looking for interesting things, you know?
Seeker: Hm.
Wellby: Here exploring. I mean, here just seeking out
Wellby: n- new experiences. I, I spent all my life wandering around the Green Sea.
Wellby: I, I went from one end of the Green Sea to the middle, because nobody goes past the middle, uh, uh, so...
Wellby: But I've never been south.
DM: Never been south.
Wellby: So wandering, uh, hopefully into the empty places on the map, and if I can't get to them, then maybe on to Chardon, maybe further south.
Unknown: Hm.
Wellby: Maybe see if there are boats that go west.
Seeker: I'm interested to learn more about the things you've seen in your travels.
Seeker: How come nobody goes beyond the middle of the Green Sea?
Wellby: Well, it just goes on and on and on.
Seeker: Uh, uh,
Unknown: um,
Wellby: there's just nothing there. It's, it's a, it's a desert, an ocean desert, you know?
Seeker: How strange.
Kenzo: I hail from Chardon.
Wellby: Really? What's Chardon like?
Kenzo: Depends which part.
DM: What... Hm.
Delwath: What is Chardon like these days?
Kenzo: These days, I don't know.
DM: Are you asking, like, out of cur- like, what would you know about it?
Delwath: No, no, no, I'm asking in character.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
Delwath: What is Chardon like these days?
Kenzo: These days, I don't know.
Kenzo: It's been years since I've been back.
Kenzo: I'm not sure I ever wanna go back, but we'll see.
Delwath: Oh, well, these da- by these days, I meant any time in the last 20, 30 years.
Kenzo: Chardon, I mean, it's still, it's still bustling.
Kenzo: It's still,
Kenzo: it's still, uh, quite the city, quite the hub, but
Unknown: I don't know.
Kenzo: It's, uh, was home once, w- was, was home o- once upon a time, but-
Unknown: Hm
Kenzo: ... I'm not eager to go back.
Kenzo: Are you, are you, are you...
Kenzo: What, what's your connection to Chardon?
Delwath: It was an important place long ago.
Kenzo: It was.
Kenzo: It was an important place long ago.
DM: So, so as you're talking, um,
DM: the, the woman who was in the fight with you returns with, um, two people.
DM: Um, one is a tall, uh, pretty handsome man, darker skin and short curly black hair.
DM: Um, he's wearing this ocher-colored robe trimmed in silver and walking slowly on a staff.
DM: He seems,
DM: you know, in the, you know, uh,
DM: healthy and strong, but just kind of looking around him as he moves.
DM: Um, the other is an older woman, um,
DM: sort of walking slowly with a cane, bent back, uh, clearly, um, you know, needing the cane to walk, and sort of leaning on the, the man's arm as
DM: she goes. Graying hair, weathered skin.
DM: Um, a- as, um,
DM: as they both enter, uh, the teahouse, um, the first thing, um, the, uh, the woman who fought with you does is she, um, runs up
Unknown: to,
Unknown: uh,
DM: to Delwath, the elf, and, um, pulls out, uh, from a pouch this, like, um,
DM: vial, this, like, um, almost, like, test tube, like, little glass tube, um, that has some, uh, uh, like, almost like,
DM: it almost looks like mud- It's like, it's like powder but that's been mixed with water or something like that.
DM: It's this reddish ochre mud.
DM: And she takes it out and she spreads it on her hands, um, and she says, uh, to Delwath, "Thanks, elf.
DM: Um, we owe you so much."
DM: And she kind of rubs the, um,
DM: this ochre mud on y- on your wound.
DM: And, and the rest of you see the wound,
Unknown: um,
DM: begins to, to close as, um, as this mud is sort of applied.
DM: And
DM: you are healed to full, Delwath.
Unknown: Um-
Delwath: I'll nod slightly and...
Delwath: Or I'll, I'll sort of bow, like nod my head graciously and say, "Thank you.
Delwath: I hesitated to ask, but it is much appreciated."
DM: She then, um, looks around and says, "Before we,
DM: uh, before we talk, uh, thank you strangers, travelers to our, to our town.
DM: With... This help unlooked for.
DM: Does a- is anybody else wounded and in need of healing?"
Kenzo: Uh, Kenzo kind of leans back in his chair to reveal this, like, gash across his chest that's, like, you know, looking better thanks to, thanks to Seeker, but, but definitely still...
DM: And he sort of like-
Unknown: She takes-
Kenzo: ... leans back and he's like, he sort of points.
Kenzo: [laughs] He's like...
Unknown: Um,
DM: she takes another one of these, um, sort of vials of this sort of muddy, muddy sort of powder, and again kind of rubs it on the wound.
DM: Um, and she says, "I..."
DM: She, like, looks up at you slightly, and awe, and, um, rec- recognizes you as, you know, Dunmari,
DM: uh, natively from here, even though y- she doesn't know you personally.
DM: And she says, um,
DM: "That was..." Almost, like, breathlessly, "That was
DM: very impressive in the fight."
DM: Um, and you are also feel full to, healed to full.
DM: And then she, um, a couple of, uh,
DM: sort of other acolytes who have been hanging out in the back sort of come in briefly.
DM: And she, with them, helps carry the body of the, um, stable but badly wounded villager, and, like, sort of nods to the man as she walks out,
DM: um, saying, "We- we'll take care of him while you chat."
DM: And then she leaves with the other-
Unknown: Kenzo?
Kenzo: Yep.
Kenzo: How... Just, just, uh, at this time, how rare is it for there...
Kenzo: Like how rare are elves, dwarves, and halflings?
Kenzo: Is this like, is this gathering, like, common or is there any particular reason that's like-
DM: Elves are super like-
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um, I mean, everybody-
Unknown: Okay. That's good to know
DM: ... calls him the elf because they've never s- nobody's seen another elf.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: Okay. Okay.
DM: So basically you've never heard anybody refer to Delwath by his name, Delwath.
DM: Like everybody who's talked to him has just called him elf or the elf.
Kenzo: The elf. I see.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Halflings and dwarves are not uncommon.
DM: So you would have seen dwarves traveling.
DM: You would have certainly seen dwarves in the, you know, where you were before, right?
DM: Halflings travel frequently around.
DM: Le- I mean, not so common here, but there would, you know, there would be a few, um,
DM: uh, you know, there would be a few that come through every year.
DM: And dwarves would, dwarves would be irregular visitors for like the, the festival, right?
DM: They'd... There's a dwarven,
DM: you know, several dwarven cities and towns in the mountains to the, um, to the southwest.
Unknown: And
DM: typically there would be d- you know, parties of dwarven merchants and traders who would come into town, even a relatively small town like this, for the, like, yearly big market.
DM: And people would buy their, you know, anvils and metal tools and things and stuff like that.
DM: Um.
Kenzo: Sure.
Unknown: Um,
DM: but yeah, elves are, elves are definitely quite rare.
DM: Uh, okay. So as, as, um, the woman and the two, uh,
DM: a- assistants, and her two assistants leave with the wounded villager, um,
Unknown: the
DM: taller man and the bent older woman introduce themselves.
DM: Um, the man, although he doesn't speak much, introduces himself as Candrosa, Speaker of Shakun,
DM: and then sort of turns to the older woman, and, who introduces herself as Elder Kisa.
Unknown: Um,
DM: and Elder Kisa begins speaking to you, and, and starts, um, speaking in a sort of slow, uh, deliberate way.
DM: Um, "Travelers,
DM: and our friend the elf,
DM: could have not have asked for a, uh, a more blessed coincidence than to have
DM: you all here at this time.
DM: I hesitate to even think what would have happened if you had not lept to our defense.
DM: Many m- would have died."
DM: And then she looks, um, again at, towards Delwath and says,
DM: "You must also think, m- must also suspect, elf, that these beasts seem to be growing stronger.
DM: One could be chance, and twice might be bad luck,
DM: but three times cannot be ignored.
DM: Something is happening."
Unknown: Yes. Yeah.
DM: "And the festival is almost upon us.
DM: I would hate to think what three or four of these could do to the market.
Unknown: Elf,
Unknown: and
DM: travelers,
Unknown: uh,
DM: do you have any idea what is happening?"
Seeker: I'd certainly like to learn more.
Seeker: The blood on the bodies of one of the h- of, of the, of these, uh, creatures suggests that they've been, uh, attacking others, uh, nearby.
Seeker: Have you heard anything, heard anything about that?
DM: Attacking others.
DM: There is not much else besides wandering herders and,
DM: and, uh, shepherds in these parts.
DM: We're the only village for some distance.
DM: Water is scarce, and it's...
DM: You know, without the oasis, we wouldn't be here.
DM: I am,
DM: I am surprised.
Seeker: Hmm.
DM: How, how did you... What did you say you saw?
Seeker: Uh, just the dried blood on the, on the corpse of one of the hyenas that we killed.
DM: Interesting.
DM: I am concerned primarily for the safety of this village.
DM: I don't know...
DM: The fact that there was others, you say, who are hurt is, uh,
Unknown: um,
DM: is, uh,
DM: comes as a, as, uh, grave news and a, and a surprise to me.
DM: And, and as she's sort of talking to you, um,
DM: Candrosa looks over at, um,
DM: at, uh, at Ken- at Kenzo, and
DM: kind of looks at him
DM: again more, more...
DM: In a sort of more deliberate and, and concentrated way, and gives a long, slow nod,
DM: and says, "My friend, welcome."
DM: Uh, and then turns back and says,
Unknown: "Kisa,
DM: you were saying?"
Unknown: Um,
DM: and then she picks up again, and she says, uh,
DM: uh... She sort of is, seems almost at a loss for words, and she, and she then turns again, like, listening to you, and sort of paying attention to everybody, but seemingly to direct her,
Seeker: her, uh,
DM: um, her attention mostly at the elf, and says, "Ca- can you help us?
DM: Maybe if this was attacking others, somebody
DM: in the village has, has seen or, or somebody who has, who has family who have returned recently for the festival.
Unknown: Would you-
Unknown: We should.
Delwath: Yes, we should investigate.
Unknown: I think,
Delwath: um, Delwath will look towards, um, Candrosa.
Delwath: Do we, do I know the name of the acolyte who was...
DM: Um,
DM: you...
DM: Yeah, I mean, you, you've s- you've se- you've seen her around.
Unknown: Um,
DM: uh, you would have,
DM: you probably would have, like, um, been introduced to her-
DM: Right
DM: ... you know, once or twice.
DM: Her na- her name is Beli.
Delwath: Beli?
Delwath: Yes.
Delwath: Um, so Delwath will say, "During, d- there seems to be some magic at work here.
Delwath: During the fight, Beli was s- trying to do something, and it wasn't working."
Seeker: Yes, I was wondering about that.
Delwath: Do you know what that might have been?
DM: He, like, takes a deep breath, and kind of,
DM: "That is,
DM: that is news.
Unknown: Um,
DM: that is news that perhaps touches upon some mysteries I may not speak of openly today.
DM: But thank you for, for that information.
DM: There are, there are secrets that puzzle me
DM: about these events, as I am sure puzzle you."
Delwath: There was a disturbance I saw.
DM: A disturbance?
Delwath: Hold on, I'm trying to find what you said.
Kenzo: [laughs] Um,
Delwath: like a distortion of the weave.
DM: He... When you say that, um,
DM: he seem, he kind of looks...
DM: He almost starts to go a little bit pale, and he looks,
Unknown: um,
DM: n- nervous, m-
DM: and kind of takes a step back and says,
Unknown: "I,
DM: I do not like the sound of such thing, my friend elf."
Delwath: It reminded me so much as nothing like...
Delwath: It reminded me like nothing so much as
DM: memory of my childhood.
DM: Your childhood?
DM: I've not heard you speak much of that time.
Delwath: You're right. That's true.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Wait, what reminded you of your childhood?
Delwath: Magic.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Something-
Seeker: There was a disruption in your childhood?
Seeker: We have to dive in.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: it reminded me so,
Kenzo: more...
Delwath: Not the distortion.
DM: The, uh,
Delwath: the flavor
Delwath: reminded me like nothing so much as
Delwath: the elven masters of old.
Seeker: The elven masters?
Delwath: And Delwath kind of goes quiet, like he's probably not gonna say anything else about that.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: uh,
DM: Candrosa also kind of goes silent at this,
DM: and
DM: kind of looks to, to Kisa, and, um...
DM: Oh, hold on.
DM: Uh.
Kenzo: I'm doing an arcana check.
DM: Yep, I got it. I got it.
DM: Um.
DM: I will say this is a lot more efficient than writing on note cards.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Um,
Unknown: um...
Kenzo: I look over at, uh...
Unknown: Oh.
Kenzo: I look over at, um,
Kenzo: at Wellby.
Kenzo: Do you know much about magic?
Unknown: I know
Wellby: 112 stories of magic.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: Muddled together: fables, fantasies, children's tales, then bits and pieces.
Wellby: I mean, you know, you pick some of these things up in your travels.
Wellby: But as for the use of it, no, that's not my style.
Wellby: To me, this all seems very straightforward.
Wellby: These things must have come from somewhere.
Wellby: We go back, we find out where it is, and, uh, either they chase us back here again or we hit them till they don't stand up.
Seeker: [laughs] Well, I'd certainly support the effort to find, uh, where they've come from.
Unknown: Yes.
Seeker: But something seems odd in this situation
Seeker: as far as where they've been.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: Well, I say we track them.
Wellby: Among the four of us, or five of us if one of them wants to come with.
Seeker: I must admit, I've come a long way just to see the temple here in this town, and I haven't had a chance to see it yet.
Seeker: I have a, a very special interest in what the, uh,
Seeker: the, uh, worshipers of, of Shakun access there.
Wellby: Well, look, I've been hanging out in this town for two weeks now waiting for a festival-
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: ... hoping that it's gonna be worth the wait.
Wellby: I think we can track this down and be back in time for the party.
Seeker: How soon is it?
DM: The, the festival's, like, uh, about two weeks.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Maybe a few weeks.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: now, Ra-
Unknown: [clears throat]
Wellby: As you're talking, um-
Wellby: Let me, let me assure you, as a person who's been in this town for two weeks, there is not two weeks worth of things to do in this town.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: When-
Kenzo: Hmm
DM: ... you say that, um, Kisa and, and Candrosa kind of look at each other and, um-
DM: Oh, no.
Delwath: Tim froze.
Delwath: Tim, you froze.
DM: Can you hear me?
Delwath: This is perfect, actually.
Wellby: As, as he turns to me to say something, I suddenly catch myself remembering [laughs] that he is sitting right there.
DM: Can you hear me?
Unknown: Yes.
Kenzo: Yes.
DM: Okay. Um,
DM: so, so, uh, Kisa kind of frowns when you say this and, and says, "I, I will
DM: forgive such comments for your valor today, but
Seeker: we...
DM: There is, there is much to love about this town."
Delwath: Delwath will also kind of look over and say,
Delwath: "I've been here six months, and I think I've barely scratched the surface on the things to do."
Wellby: Yeah, but you're really old.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: How old are you, Ulf?
Kenzo: I was born...
Delwath: What, what would people call the Battle of Cha'mut, Tim?
DM: Um, like, the Great Battle or the, or the...
DM: The War.
DM: It's the War, right? It's, like-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... the only thing that is so earth-shatteringly covering the whole, whole continent that it's called the War.
Delwath: I was born 100 years before the War.
Unknown: Whoa.
DM: Uh-
Wellby: I'll hastily try and walk it back and say, "Well, I...
Wellby: Forgive me. Forgive me. Obviously, I'm a traveler passing through.
Wellby: My interests are different than yours.
Wellby: It's rude of me to cast aspersions on a city that's offered nothing but kind hospitality.
Seeker: Please forgive me."
Seeker: 100 years before the War.
DM: So as y- as this conversation is, is, um, continuing, um, Candrosa, who's looked, um, kind of,
Unknown: uh,
DM: sort of nervous ever since the conversation about magic, turns to Kisa and turns to Delwath and says, um, "I must go check on, um,
DM: on Beli and, and my acolytes and the wounded."
DM: And he then turns to Kenzo, and he gives you another slow nod and says, um, "We will speak later, my friend."
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: And then walks out.
Kenzo: Wait, um, w- uh, I, I've only...
Kenzo: I've been here a day, right? I got here yesterday?
DM: No, you got here, like, 20 minutes ago.
Kenzo: Oh, shit. Yeah. So, so before he leaves I, I, I say, um, "Where am I, where am I staying again?"
Kenzo: Just to, to-
DM: You, you don't have anywhere.
DM: I mean, you-
Kenzo: Oh, shit. Okay. Um-
DM: You literally saw...
DM: were walking into town when you saw this inn.
Unknown: Right, right, right.
Kenzo: I... Wait, before Candrosa leaves, I, I just say to him, um, "Where shall I find you?"
DM: "I, I am at the temple most of the time.
DM: You will know the way."
Kenzo: Okay. I'll seek you there.
Unknown: Be well.
DM: Um, and then
DM: a- as he leaves, uh, Kisa
DM: also looks, looks at Delwath and says, um, "I must,
DM: I must go
DM: attend to the, to the villagers and try and calm, calm them down.
DM: You have aided us several times before, but the third time pays for all."
DM: Can I leave this matter in your capable hands, good elf?
Unknown: Of course.
DM: And then she'll leave.
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: So Delweth will sort of turn to the three of you and say, "I could use some assistance in, uh,
Delwath: tracking these things down.
Delwath: You all, I think, have reasons to be here, but perhaps you could spare a day to, uh,
Delwath: see if we can learn anything."
Kenzo: Delweth, I, I'll be honest, I, I think the last time I saw an elf was when I was a young boy, and,
Kenzo: uh, it's, it's, it's quite a, quite, quite something to meet you and see you.
Kenzo: So I, I'd be delighted to spend more time, yes.
Delwath: You know Candrosa?
Kenzo: I know of Candrosa.
Delwath: Candrosa seems to know you.
Seeker: Hmm.
Kenzo: We, uh, we share a, a, uh,
Kenzo: we share an understanding.
Kenzo: Let's, let's, let's leave it at that for now.
Delwath: Delweth looks quite interested.
Kenzo: I, I, I, I gauge her interest and continue, and also look very interested at you.
Unknown: Um.
Delwath: Perhaps we can continue this conversation, uh, in a more civilized fashion, uh, when there are not giant hyenas knocking at the door.
Kenzo: That would be delightful.
Kenzo: I, I literally was, I just arrived from, from above the hill, uh, to see this scene unfolding.
Unknown: I'm, uh,
Kenzo: it seems good fortune would have brought us together, as I am seeking some of the similar things that you are as well.
Kenzo: This place is new to me, but, uh, if you've all been here before, I'm glad to help and, and learn more from you all what, what, what's happening in this town.
Kenzo: And I do seek, uh, I do, I do look to spend more time with Candrosa.
Kenzo: You, you know Candrosa well?
Kenzo: Not well.
Delwath: I know of Candrosa well.
Seeker: Hmm.
Unknown: He's, uh,
Delwath: the mysteries are
Delwath: closely held.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: I would be very curious
Seeker: to visit this, uh, temple of Shakun,
Seeker: and learn anything that we can about the disturbance that is ongoing.
Seeker: Uh, that, uh, might help us in tracking down the source of the trouble.
Unknown: It might not,
Seeker: but, uh, I'm also curious to, uh, to make some notes and, and, and diagrams and findings as I do.
Kenzo: [laughs] Seeker, I share your interest in the temple.
Unknown: Ah.
Seeker: Very good. Very good.
Wellby: If these things came from the east or the south, I have an unlimited amount of time to spend on this journey.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: But we should move fast.
Wellby: If we wanna track them then-
Delwath: We should
Delwath: ... those tracks will soon-
Delwath: I was just gonna suggest that.
DM: Hmm.
Delwath: I think, um, maybe we should, uh, take a short
Delwath: refreshment and, and, um, take a short rest, in D&D terms.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: And then, um,
Delwath: and then see if we can, uh, A, see if we can find their tracks.
Delwath: Although I fear they may not have walked in from the outside.
Unknown: What do you mean?
Unknown: It,
Delwath: it's morning. Don't you think somebody would've seen them if they just strolled in from the nearest, uh,
Delwath: outskirts of the village?
Seeker: So perhaps they've been transported here somehow.
Unknown: So I mean, you are-
Kenzo: The other question...
Delwath: We are on, I guess we're on the edge
DM: ... the topography of the town is such that if they had come straight from
DM: out, you know, if they had come from due east, basically, the first, and just came across the desert, the first place in the town they would've hit would've been this.
Seeker: Hmm.
DM: There are, so there are, um, you know, there's a few buildings and stuff-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... like, but, you know, this is pretty much the edge of town.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: But we could also ask and see, um...
Seeker: What's so funny, Kenzo?
Delwath: Kenzo's having an amusing thought dropped on him from the sky.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: No, just... [laughs]
DM: Oh, did you read my message?
Kenzo: Uh,
Kenzo: yeah, but no one...
Unknown: I don't know.
DM: Oh, that's not it.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: What's going on, you guys?
Wellby: You know, it strikes me that at the end of this, Tim is going to read all of our private chat messages with each other.
Kenzo: Can you do that?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I can. I can download them afterward.
DM: Welcome to Zoom.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: This is, this is, this is something. Okay.
Unknown: Uh,
Kenzo: well, we'll, all, all shall be revealed at some point soon, I guess.
Unknown: Uh.
DM: Okay, so what do you guys wanna do?
Seeker: How far are we from this temple?
Seeker: Like, what direction is it in?
DM: The town's small, right?
DM: I mean, it's, there's probably fewer than 200 people that live here during the winter, except the few weeks around the festival.
DM: It would take you 20, 30 minutes, most, to walk from the no- you're, you're sort of at the northeast side of town, and the temple is the southeast-
DM: South center of town, but it couldn't take you more than 20 or 30 minutes to walk there.
Delwath: Well, I wanna take another 30 minutes and finish the short rest and get my spell slot back.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: And then-
Delwath: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: So I'll always-
Kenzo: I'm gonna interrupt, too.
Seeker: Spell... Oh, spell slots.
Unknown: Tim, I-
DM: You don't get yours back with a short rest.
DM: You need to sleep.
Unknown: Oh.
Wellby: Oh, but the-
DM: But it's just the one spell.
DM: It's the healing words, so you should still have another slot.
Seeker: Okay. Um, I can't-
Unknown: But then, well-
Delwath: But then the other thing is I wanna track them.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah. Well, let's say, let's, let's meet right back here in 30 minutes.
Wellby: I gotta go gear up.
Kenzo: Yeah. Uh, wait. Before, before you all depart, what, what tavern should I be...
Kenzo: I, I literally just walked into town.
Unknown: What, what is the thing?
DM: There's just one tavern.
Delwath: It's across the street.
Unknown: There's one.
Delwath: The one tavern.
Delwath: That one.
Kenzo: If that's the one, let me settle my things, and I'll, I'll, I'll reconvene with you out here.
Seeker: Wait, so it's a 30-minute round trip, I hope, to the temple?
DM: I, I mean, you could... You... If you were-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: If you wanted to hustle on your little dwarf legs, you could, you could probably, like, get there and back in 30, 40 minutes.
Seeker: I'm highly motivated.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: Okay. I mean, yeah, okay.
DM: So, uh, Seeker's gonna go look at the temple.
Unknown: Um,
DM: uh...
Kenzo: Kenzo's taking his time, man.
Kenzo: This is, this is... We're gonna be here for... What's the name of the town again?
DM: Karawa.
Kenzo: Karawa.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: So-
Kenzo: Kenzo goes, uh, Kenzo goes, makes friends with the, the, uh, uh, the tavern owner, and, um, you know, explains he might be here for a little while.
Kenzo: Gets a room.
DM: Okay. So, so that's what you're gonna do.
DM: We're gonna have to do more breakout rooms.
DM: But, um,
DM: here, I'll, uh,
Unknown: um...
DM: I'll just do it by text, 'cause that's probably more efficient.
DM: What... So you're going to the, to the tavern across the way.
DM: Kong is doing that. Eric's going to the temple.
DM: Mike's resting.
Kenzo: Wait, where's... Mike, where are you resting?
Kenzo: Are you resting at the tavern-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... or are you re-
Delwath: No, no, I'm... This... My, my rooms are above this tea house.
Delwath: I'm just staying in the tea house.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
Delwath: I'll be at our table in a half hour, the table we've been sitting at and talking.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: I'm gonna, uh,
Wellby: pack my bags, put on my armor, and settle my bill.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Very responsible.
DM: Uh, okay. So...
Kenzo: And, uh, actually, when I, when I, um...
Kenzo: Ugh, hmm.
Kenzo: When I, when I... After I deal with the tavern, um, if I'm able to, I try to find, uh, Taelgar.
Delwath: Yeah, I'm sitting here. Like, you come back, he's just...
Delwath: I'm not sleeping or anything.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Like, I'm just sitting at the table-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... slowly enjoying a cup of tea and kinda staring off into space.
Kenzo: Perfect. Can we breakout room, and can I talk with elf?
DM: Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
DM: Okay.
DM: Can you do that, then?
DM: Um, yes. I'll put you both in a,
Unknown: um...
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: So you're both in breakout room three now, if you just go join those breakout rooms.
Unknown: Nice.
DM: Oh, wait a minute.
DM: I'll be right back.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Tim?
DM: Hey, Kong, I had a message I had to send you, but it wouldn't let me send it to you when you were in the breakout room.
Delwath: I don't think Kong's actually here, or at least I don't...
Delwath: He's not talking.
Delwath: I think his computer... He, we lost his, uh...
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: It's, it's-
DM: Uh, okay. So-
DM: ... truly many hundreds of miles.
Wellby: But you've been making this map of the ley lines.
Seeker: Oh, yes. Oh, yes. It's original research.
Wellby: Oh, wow. I pull out from my pack, and I spread out the map that I've been making of my travels down from, um-
Wellby: Oh, dear
Wellby: ... uh, Sembara down this way.
Seeker: Uh, we should, we should compare notes sometime.
Seeker: [laughs] This is fantastic.
Unknown: Tim?
Kenzo: Should I go back to the other room?
Unknown: Kong?
DM: What's going on?
DM: I don't know what's happened to Kong.
Unknown: Uh...
Delwath: He's not in the other room?
DM: No, I'm gonna text him.
Unknown: Um,
DM: we, we seem to have lost Kong.
Seeker: Oh, no.
DM: Oh, no.
DM: Um, I just texted him.
DM: Uh, okay, but you want to...
Unknown: So
DM: if you're done chatting with each other, um,
DM: Seeker was gonna go look at the temple, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay.
DM: Uh, and you sent me a message.
DM: Um...
DM: Okay, so,
Seeker: um...
DM: Uh. Mm-hmm.
Seeker: Oh, um, right.
Seeker: This skill that I've, um, been cultivating my entire life but also have never used before.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: hmm.
Seeker: Let's read, [laughs] let's read about it.
DM: So yeah,
DM: I also just made it up, so that may be-
Seeker: Mm-hmm
Seeker: ... two. [laughs]
Seeker: Um.
DM: I think you don't, I'm not sure-
DM: Kong has vanished.
Delwath: Does anybody know what's happened to him?
Unknown: I texted him.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: I texted him.
DM: Oh, he's back.
Seeker: Um.
DM: He's trying to come back.
DM: Okay, so I got it.
DM: Here's the, uh, I'm gonna, I'm gonna send you a message.
Wellby: Man,
Seeker: it's pretty surreal to be wearing glasses.
Seeker: Okay. But I'm be- I'm doing scholarly things now, so it's appropriate.
DM: Oh. Oh, that's...
Seeker: Oh, dear, that's very interesting.
Seeker: Hmm.
Seeker: Um.
Seeker: Hmm, hmm, hmm, hmm.
DM: Now, if you want to try and figure out more about what it is, um, you can make an intelligence check.
Seeker: Oh, oh, I sure do.
Seeker: Let's see. Intelligence check.
DM: Aw.
DM: Yeah, you can't, um, you can't really...
Unknown: Here.
Unknown: [coughs]
Unknown: Oh.
Seeker: Hmm.
Seeker: I can't chat to you, Tim, for some reason.
Seeker: It says, "Timothy Sackton is not in this meeting."
Seeker: That's odd.
DM: Um, just send the message anyway.
Delwath: It doesn't let, it doesn't let you, uh...
Seeker: Oh, there we go. It worked.
Seeker: Just had to reselect Tim.
Seeker: For some reason it changed.
Seeker: Um,
Seeker: uh,
Seeker: huh. I wonder if there's anything else I can do here.
Seeker: Detect Magic would used up one of my,
Unknown: or would use up-
DM: That only has a range of 30 feet.
DM: Oh, yeah, so never mind that.
Seeker: Um,
Seeker: hmm.
Seeker: Okay, okay.
DM: Well, uh.
Unknown: Hey.
DM: Kong, you're back.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Everybody good?
Unknown: Well, there was something-
DM: Kong, did you get the-
Kenzo: ... that like spun forever, and then I, I, I logged out of Zoom.
DM: Sorry about that.
DM: Did, did you get the message I sent you?
DM: Let me double check.
DM: I'll send, I just sent it again.
DM: Okay, I think we should now all reconvene, just in the interest of time.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Okay, so I come, uh, hustling back, panting a little bit, and, um, stuffing scrolls back into a s- scroll case.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Oh, Kong looks really weird.
Seeker: What happened to you, Kong?
Delwath: He, has he frozen?
Seeker: He's having-
DM: Looks like a cloud a little bit also.
Delwath: It does a little bit.
DM: Kong's having some tech difficulties.
Unknown: Um.
Delwath: So, um, what's-
DM: Uh, uh, Kong's frozen now.
DM: Okay, here, we're coming back.
Delwath: He's joining a second time.
DM: Can you guys hear me? Yep.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm, yep.
Seeker: It really looks like I'm wearing glasses.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Can you hear me? Yep.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Yep. Yep, yep.
Seeker: Oh, but he can't hear us. Now he can.
Delwath: Okay. Can you hear us?
DM: Yes, yeah, sorry.
Unknown: Yo.
Kenzo: I'm listening on my computer right now. It's bugging out with Zoom, but apologies y'all
DM: All right
DM: Okay, so you're all returning back to the,
DM: to the tea house
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Seeker: And I'm, uh, I'm making some notes
Kenzo: What did you find at the temple, friend?
Seeker: Well, as I suspected, there is an incredible convergence here
Seeker: of the lines of power inside of the temple.
Seeker: Well, I'm not sure about that, actually.
Seeker: I didn't go inside.
Seeker: The convergence is, is surely inside of the mesa itself.
Seeker: I did also notice,
Seeker: uh, that there's, uh, some kind of, uh,
Seeker: uh, concentration of valuable stone.
Seeker: Uh, but I, I, I couldn't, I couldn't quite pin down what it was.
Seeker: Something in there.
Unknown: Hmm.
Seeker: I don't know if that's relevant or not.
Kenzo: What kind of stone?
Seeker: I, I couldn't quite figure it out.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: perhaps we can arrange, uh, a temple tour from the speaker
Seeker: at some point in the future.
Seeker: Perhaps.
Delwath: I have not been able to so far, but perhaps.
Seeker: Hmm. They're secretive about the interior.
Delwath: Quite.
Seeker: Guess they don't call it mysteries for nothing.
Seeker: Ah.
Unknown: Hmm.
Seeker: I wish these religious types would be more open to the, uh, benefit of free scholarly transaction.
Seeker: Alas.
Kenzo: There's always secrets.
Seeker: I guess that's what keeps it interesting.
Delwath: Should we perhaps, um,
Delwath: go investigate these, uh, giant hyenas?
Seeker: Yeah. Who, who's got a skill in, in tracking the, the movements of animals among us?
DM: I do.
Seeker: Oh, very good.
DM: Oh, there we go. It's a good roll, too.
Seeker: Boom.
DM: Um, okay. So,
DM: uh, it takes you...
DM: Yeah, who else is-
DM: Oh, wow. [laughs]
Seeker: Word.
Unknown: Um,
DM: so the two of you, um, spend some time searching around for tracks.
DM: Um, so the...
DM: Right within town, the tracks are very scuffled from the fight, and you can't really make much sense of that.
DM: But the, um, you know, taking a sort of survey around the outskirts of town, just kind of following, um, back to, uh, where the,
DM: the... You can sort of see the entry point where they sort of came into the town.
DM: And, um, you do indeed see the tracks of two of these beasts, large, um, claw prints of something that matches what this, uh,
DM: what this beast must have been, um, heading to the east.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
Seeker: Shall we do-
Delwath: Do we follow them?
DM: Yeah. Here we go.
Kenzo: Please, lead, lead the way.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: I'm gonna get my, my horse and some supplies-
Unknown: A horse
Delwath: ... just in case we're out here for more than, like-
Unknown: All right
DM: ... an hour.
Unknown: Mm.
Wellby: Okay.
Wellby: Oh, I'm, I'm totally geared up.
Wellby: So when I come back down and meet up again, I've got on, uh, studded leather armor, and, uh,
Wellby: a quiver of arrows at my side, and a bow in hand, and my, my pack on.
Unknown: Uh,
Wellby: not planning to come back for a little while if we have to.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Okay. So you set out of town, um, heading east into the desert.
Unknown: Uh,
DM: I guess the only one who's not totally geared up for long travel is
Delwath: Seeker.
DM: I mean, you're mostly,
Unknown: um,
DM: you know, fol- You're mostly, um, you know, you've got, uh, the else, Delweth's horse.
DM: And, um, Wellby is, you know, tromps out of the, out of the caravan, sort of like with a full explorer's, like, get-up, basically.
DM: Um, seems like he could travel for weeks, like several water bottles hanging off of his, off of his back.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: You know, a little pouch with, like, snacks and stuff.
DM: Um, you're certainly well-prepared.
Seeker: Um,
DM: as you head off into the-
DM: I've got ink.
Seeker: What?
Seeker: I have plenty of ink.
DM: You have ink and maps.
DM: Um, you head off into the, sort of into the, um, desert, heading sort of east, slightly north of east.
Unknown: Um,
DM: the, the terrain is-
Kenzo: Are we all walking?
Kenzo: Are we all walking or are we on horseback?
DM: I assume you're walking. The horse is probably just carrying supplies.
Kenzo: Supplies. Oh, okay. Perfect. Okay, great.
Unknown: Um, yes.
DM: You, you continue for sort of maybe half a day, uh, uh, traveling through the sort of desert landscape, s- uh, sort of scrubby brush
DM: most of-
Delwath: Um, um, I'll, I'll leave a word with the tea house, too, to send a note to, um, what's her name, the village elder, that we're gonna
Delwath: f- that we're gonna follow the tracks at least for a day's journey-
Unknown: Okay
Delwath: ... and see what we can find.
DM: So the, the desert here is mostly sort of, uh, you know,
DM: s- sort of scrubby plants,
DM: thorn bushes, the, you know, the occasional, like, um,
DM: rocky boulder cliff, uh- Lots of, lots of stuff in bloom.
DM: It's been a relatively wet winter, and so, um, the, the plants are thriving.
DM: Like, you even see some, some patches that almost look green.
DM: Um, away to the south in the distance, up in the sort of southeastern part of town, is, um, it is an area where there's some agriculture.
DM: There's like, uh, date palms that are grown and a few other crops, and so you can see them sort of off to the south.
DM: But the tracks are heading more in a northeasterly direction.
DM: It's relatively easy travel for, you know, two, three hours or so.
Unknown: Um,
DM: heading gently up, um, sort of vaguely in the direction of, of the sort of old trade road that, um,
DM: Wellby you would have came into town on, but that's a bit, that's far to the north from here.
DM: But you're sort of angling. You sort of feel like you're angling in a direction to head.
DM: Um, until after about three, four hours travel, um, following these tracks, uh,
DM: the, the...
DM: You sort of climb up a little bit and get to a, a stretch of hard rock.
DM: And it's not entire- I mean, you can look around if you'd like, but the tracks which, um, were relatively straightforward to follow now seem to just kind of disappear
DM: into the
Unknown: rock.
Kenzo: Disappear into the rock?
DM: No, I mean, it's just like y-
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Following tracks through loose sand is pretty easy, but now you're-
Unknown: Got it
DM: ... on bare rock and-
DM: ... and just based on your experience, it's not quite so simple to follow them anymore.
Kenzo: Got it.
Seeker: And I have this, like, stone cunning thing, like rocks, like I know.
Seeker: But doesn't mean I can see tracks that aren't there, I guess.
DM: No, and, and that's... I mean, you're, you're good at, at construction, right?
DM: You're good at, like... And you're good at, at geology, but you're not good at, like,
DM: uh, things walking over rocks.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Hmm. I could, I could tell if someone was to traverse it where they might go, I suppose.
DM: Uh, you could, you could kind of look or you could maybe get a sense from the landscape of, you know, the topography of the land and kind of what the, the easiest routes forward
DM: would be, but there's no guarantee that anybody would follow the sort of path of least resistance.
Seeker: Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Delwath: I mean, are you say, is the rock stretch gigantic?
Delwath: Or is it like-
Unknown: Uh-
Delwath: ... you spend an hour just walking around trying to see where the tracks resume?
DM: Uh, you can look, you can certainly look around.
DM: You can, and make another survival check, but it can, it's, it's like, uh, you've gone from a kind of, um, uh,
DM: you've, you've gone from a, um,
DM: a desert area that's mostly, like, scrub and rock and sand to basically one that's hard rock, and, um, extending into sort of in the distance, you see...
DM: I mean, the rock continues for a while.
DM: It's not like a, like a, a, a rock outcropping with sand on the other side.
DM: It's like you're coming, uh, it's like the terrain is shifting.
DM: Um, and you, Seeker, would know from your experience that, um, you know, this, you've been going up a little bit, and you're probably getting to a sort of more, more cliffy and,
DM: um, solid as opposed to a sort of dirt and scrub part of the terrain.
DM: And it's not,
DM: if this continues to ascend, you might just get to just sort of bare rocks continuing for days.
DM: It's hard to tell.
Unknown: Um,
DM: it, y- you don't have a good sense of, of
DM: that the terrain will shift s- shortly to something that's easy to track.
Seeker: Where are we with respect to ley lines?
DM: Uh,
DM: there aren't any ley lines immediately in, within 30 feet of you.
Kenzo: And I have a, a insight plus five.
Kenzo: Does that help me here for anything? Can I do, like, an insight check, or does that not help?
DM: That just helps, uh, with,
DM: with people, not so much with-
Kenzo: Ah. Not with rocks.
DM: Not with rocks.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Okay. Okay.
Kenzo: What should we do now?
Kenzo: Feels like we've gotten to a dead end.
Seeker: Hmm.
Wellby: How steady was the direction of travel that we were following?
Wellby: Is it more or less straight?
Wellby: I mean, can we sort of make a good guess?
Wellby: Or was it more meandering?
DM: Um, I mean, it was sort of meandering around obstacles.
DM: Like, it, it, you know, there's, there'll be like a rock,
Unknown: um,
DM: you know, jutting out or something.
DM: It, it wasn't, uh,
DM: you know, it wasn't a... And then it would sort of meander off course a little bit, and it would kind of, um, come back.
DM: It, it, it seemed like it was heading in a direction, but not a straight line.
Delwath: So, I mean, let's just keep going in the direction it was heading for another
Seeker: 45 minutes.
Wellby: I think so. I was gonna say a few hours, but at least, yeah.
Seeker: Sure.
Kenzo: Mike, we can't hear you very well, by the way.
Kenzo: Or unless I'm the only one that can't hear.
DM: Yeah, I can hear that.
Delwath: I said, is that better?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah, that's-
Delwath: I, I think my mic slipped off my headset.
Delwath: Um, the, let's keep going for an hour at least in the general direction they were going.
Delwath: We should have some idea of what direction they were traveling.
DM: Oh, yeah, definitely. I mean, they were going, they w- it, they've been traveling, um,
DM: roughly speaking, you're h- you've been heading, um,
DM: heading northeast or east northeast, like very roughly speaking, with, with some twists and turns.
Unknown: Um-
Unknown: Right
Unknown: Can you-
DM: Okay, so y-
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Sorry, go ahead.
Seeker: Can you use Detect Magic for tracking?
Seeker: Like, do things leave traces as they move across surfaces?
DM: Uh.
Seeker: Are there magic fomites?
DM: [laughs] Y- I mean, so in order to sense ley lines, you would've, uh, you would've ca- I mean, you would've had to take a few minutes to cast Detect
DM: Magic as a ritual.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Right? So you can't just see the ley lines.
DM: And so if there was magic, you would've sensed it.
DM: You don't sense any magic.
Seeker: Got it. Thank you.
Unknown: What's the, what's-
Kenzo: Tell, do you think these hyenas are m- you, you think these, uh, these, uh, hyenas are magical in nature?
Seeker: It's a open question, I think.
Delwath: Uh, perhaps.
Delwath: Or they were, um-
Unknown: Altered
DM: ... were magically altered.
Unknown: Mm.
Kenzo: Or they were, um,
Delwath: magically compelled.
Unknown: Hm.
Unknown: What's this on-
Unknown: I mean,
Delwath: two hyenas would not be hunting in broad daylight.
Delwath: I mean, I'm saying this out of character, but-
Unknown: Mm
Delwath: ... like, from a nature perspective, there's clearly something weird going on here.
Delwath: Even weird giant hyenas would g- generally not be, uh, would generally not be hunting in-
Unknown: Mm
Delwath: ... a pack of only two into a town.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: I assume.
Kenzo: What do you all know of the, what do you all know of...
DM: Oh, you froze again there, Kong.
Kenzo: No, I heard him.
DM: No, no, you're good. What did you say?
Kenzo: What do you all know of the Shakun?
Seeker: Well, from what I-
Unknown: Wow.
Unknown: Oh.
Delwath: No, no, Seeker,
Delwath: share your wisdom.
Seeker: [laughs] I think you know more than I.
Kenzo: I know, I know very little.
DM: Hm.
Delwath: I've been, um, curious about them for some time,
Delwath: but they've revealed their secrets very, um,
Kenzo: begrudgingly.
Seeker: Mm.
Unknown: Hm.
Seeker: While, uh, residing in that town, Delwath,
Seeker: did it ever happen that you've had strange dreams?
Wellby: Why do you ask?
Seeker: I have reason to suspect a connection
DM: between
Seeker: the realm of magical powers that forms the ley lines, and is the source of many of our abilities, and another realm of magical power.
Seeker: And that perhaps, if the rumors are true,
Seeker: this mystery cult has something to do with that point of connection.
Unknown: Could all be-
Delwath: Hold on. I have, I have to ask Tim something.
Unknown: Hold on.
Unknown: Perhaps
Seeker: I traveled hundreds of miles to get here, nearly got killed by a couple of gigantic hyenas, just to investigate a connection that wasn't there,
Seeker: and I'll keep, keep traveling on.
Kenzo: What, what dreams have you had then, Seeker?
Unknown: Oh,
Seeker: I long to explore that world.
Seeker: I spent some time with the lizard folk, who have a deep connection to that area,
Seeker: but they couldn't tell me much about the architecture, you might say,
Seeker: how it's made up, and how it connects to the other parts of our world.
Delwath: So Delwath looks kind of lost in thought, like he's sort of,
Unknown: um,
Delwath: sorta seems to be staring off into space a bit, and, like, he looks a little, like...
Delwath: You, you... Anybody who would be paying attention, you, you know what, Kong, you have a good insight roll.
Delwath: I'll tell you what he, what he, uh-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... what you would notice.
Kenzo: Yeah. I've got a, I've got a very strong insight.
Kenzo: Very perceptive.
Delwath: Um, I just need to think of how to phrase this.
Unknown: Hm.
Unknown: S-
DM: So as this conversation is happening, you're still kind of s- heading across the hard stone desert, like, just kind of heading roughly northeast, hoping that you will
DM: s- see something kinda relevant to,
DM: that might help you find the trail again.
Seeker: Looking for the gigantic scat of gigantic hyenas.
Seeker: Yeah.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Or looking for the-
Kenzo: Badya, do you-
Wellby: Looking for the remains of someone they might have eaten out here too.
Seeker: Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Seeker, have you dreamed of this place?
Kenzo: Kind of glancing around.
Seeker: Oh, no, I surely haven't.
Delwath: I, I sent you a message, Kong.
Unknown: So,
DM: you know, o- over the, over the past 20 or 30 minutes or so, the terrain is getting more, um,
DM: more sort of convoluted, and you occasionally see these, like, little slot canyons going off in sort of blind alleys.
DM: Um, and,
DM: uh, it's becoming rockier and sort of harder to, to keep going forward.
Unknown: Um,
DM: the... It's almost as if you're entering more of a, almost, like, more of a badlands than a, um, than a desert, right?
DM: It's like little canyons, like little, like, you know, more kind of ru- not rubble exactly, but, like, rock formations.
DM: Like, um, it's very pretty.
DM: It's like, you know, you see the, um...
DM: Seeker, especially, you notice the, like, layers of sandstone in these slot canyons.
DM: Um- And the, there's this, all this like red and ochre color sort of through the, the, the rock.
DM: Um, but it's,
DM: it's quite, um,
DM: tricky now to sort of pick your way forward as it's not clear, um...
DM: It, it's not always easy to find a w- a, a way forward that is east,
DM: right? You're try- or northeast, right?
DM: You're trying to head east-northeast.
Unknown: Right.
DM: But sometimes you'll find your way blocked by, by a canyon, by like one of these little box canyons, and you'll have to head north.
DM: Um, and so you're beginning to feel like you're not actually sure, um-
Seeker: I can shift stone out of the way to some degree, but yeah.
DM: Yeah, I mean you-
Seeker: I can make difficult terrain easy terrain.
Delwath: So as we're walking...
Delwath: Well, I, actually, no, I'll, I'll, I'll wait.
Delwath: Hold on. I need to just hear what...
Delwath: I need, Kong needs to respond to my question first, [laughs] which requires him to respond to his question.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: [laughs] I'm just looking at sedimenta- sedimentary layers,
Unknown: you know?
Seeker: Oh, that's a good one, Schwartz.
DM: Yeah, that's, that's...
DM: I mean, it's not, it, it's maybe a little less dramatic than that, but that's kind of the idea,
DM: right? It's, uh, you're getting definitely into more, more of this sort of terrain.
DM: So, um,
DM: uh, Wellby, can you make another survival check?
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: So,
DM: um, at this point, um, the elf and,
DM: and, um, Kenzo have kind of fallen behind a little bit in our, in our talking.
Unknown: And
DM: Seeker, the Seeker seems to be kind of, um, distracted by
DM: the geology of the terrain, and you're kind of looking around, like,
DM: "Uh, uh, I, I'm not entirely sure which way is the way we're supposed to be going or actually
DM: came from."
Unknown: Yeah. Hmm.
DM: And you're sort of starting to feel like you're getting turned...
DM: Everybody's, by default, just kind of let you lead, and you started to feel like you're getting turned around a bit in these canyons, and you're actually not...
DM: You now have been maybe going an hour into this rock, and you're pretty sure you could find your way back to the sort of sandy scrub desert, but
DM: you're starting to question yourself a little bit.
Seeker: Hmm.
Wellby: Can I sort of have us pause, and let's go up to a high point and just try and get the lay of the land?
Wellby: Like, is there a,
Wellby: a hill or something that we can just, you know, take a close look at-
DM: Um
Wellby: ... everywhere around us?
DM: Yeah, definitely. So, so you sort of, m- uh, ended up, uh, kind of, sort of almost down in like these little sort of canyon land areas.
Unknown: Um,
DM: you could definitely climb up.
DM: It would, uh...
DM: To get to the...
DM: It's mostly the sort of, you know, cliffs and stuff, so it's not trivial, but make a athletics check.
Seeker: I can make stairs.
DM: Oh, that... Yeah, you could make-
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: This is my mind.
Seeker: Well, with runes.
Wellby: I start, like, putting, like, chalk on my hands and things to get ready, and then...
DM: And then you turn around, it's like, "Oh, wait."
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: So, um, I don't think you can, I don't think you can shift solid stone.
DM: Um-
Unknown: What?
Unknown: Ugh.
DM: Let me see what it says.
Seeker: Doot, doot, doot.
Unknown: Ah.
Seeker: Dirt or stone fits within a five-foot cube.
Seeker: Oh, it's a short stairway.
Unknown: [laughs] Hmm.
Seeker: And then d- and deposit it f- up to five feet away.
Unknown: Um-
Unknown: Because-
DM: You can only... If it's, it's on- You can only excavate it, though, if it's loose earth.
DM: Like, you can't ch- you can't create a staircase out of a canyon wall because that's actually, like, a fifth level spell.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Hmm.
Seeker: Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
DM: Create a staircase.
DM: You can... Well, like mold, mold stone or sort of like shape stone or something like that.
Unknown: Um,
DM: you can create, like, images and, and patterns or colors, and you can cause difficult terrain to become,
DM: uh, normal terrain or normal terrain to become difficult terrain.
DM: But you can't, um...
DM: And you can dig out loose earth, so you could, you could use it to excavate loose earth and, like, pack it down and, like, build a dirt staircase up.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: But it would take quite some time.
DM: It would probably take you the rest of the day.
Unknown: I see.
DM: It's not like you can just magically carve stairs into a stone wall.
Seeker: Well-
Wellby: I've, I've got a rope and a grappling hook to, uh-
Delwath: Yeah, like-
Seeker: That sounds good
Wellby: ... yeah, and assistance, uh-
Delwath: Magic doesn't need to solve all problems.
DM: Okay. Uh, so make a-
DM: Athletics? Acrobatics?
DM: Make a dex check to throw your, just a straight dex.
Kenzo: Wait, you're throwing a grappling hook?
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Wellby: Yep.
Delwath: Wait, how far do you need to throw this grappling hook?
Wellby: To the top of the nearest canyon wall.
Kenzo: Well, you probably, I did a good job.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Like 20 feet.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Does he make it?
Unknown: Uh-
DM: He rolled a 19.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I'm sure he does.
DM: He, yeah, you make it.
Unknown: Um.
Unknown: All right.
DM: So you climb... So okay, so you're, like, climbing up the rope.
Unknown: Um,
DM: it's actually a lot harder to climb ropes than you, um,
DM: you know, that are just hooked on top.
DM: So make an athletics check just to climb the rope.
DM: Athletics or acrobatics?
DM: Athletics.
Kenzo: All right.
Seeker: It's just pure strength
Seeker: ... does this campaign, does this campaign end with us dying of thirst?
DM: It might. [laughs]
Wellby: That was a natural 20.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Hey.
DM: So you climb up to the top and, um, so you're, you've sort of found your way into this sort of box canyon.
DM: You managed to climb up to the top of the canyon, and also, um, sort of there's one kind of lower wall and one higher wall, and you're climbed up the top of the higher wall, and there's sort of a loose
DM: stone hill on top of that which you can scramble on top of.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
DM: And looking around from here, you actually haven't come that far.
DM: It's actually pretty easy to...
DM: Like, you've only come,
DM: what, like a third of a mile or a half a mile on the stone.
DM: And so from this perspective, like you can see the village in the distance.
DM: You can see the mesa anyway.
Wellby: The village itself is a little-
DM: Yeah.
DM: So it's like obvious how you get home.
DM: It's a little less obvious what's to the east.
DM: Like, this sort of, um, canyon land seems to, seems to carry on for a distance and it, um,
DM: some ways ahead, considerably further than the mesa of the village is from your current vantage point, um, you can see just the sort of shadow of what looks like
DM: a much deeper canyon sort of cutting through the...
DM: Not like Grand Canyon in scale, but that kind of style, right?
DM: Like a river valley type canyon cutting through the terrain, and beyond it's all sort of hazy and misty.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: As now you're sort of in the noon- you're in the early afternoon sun, so you know, it's, even though it's still spring, it's-
Wellby: Can I, can I like perception to look for movement or animals or dead bodies lying around or?
Unknown: Sure.
DM: [laughs] Um,
Kenzo: so
DM: you spend a while just kind of concentrating and sort of squinting in the distance.
Seeker: Um,
DM: you don't, you, you don't see anything.
DM: You don't like see any like dead bodies lying on the ground or any like obvious, um, movement.
Unknown: Um,
DM: but you do see,
DM: uh, sort of more to the north of you what looks like, um,
DM: dust being kicked up, like, uh,
DM: like if horses or, you know, animals with hooves were kind of moving at a
DM: n- non-walk pace,
DM: right? Like that sort of dust cloud.
DM: It's, it's certainly not a like just a natural dust storm or something.
DM: It's dust being kicked up by some animal moving.
Seeker: Hmm.
Wellby: Well, I'll shout back down to the three of you at the bottom of the canyon everything.
Wellby: We got animal dust to the north, and Tim, that does not line up with like where people would be coming in for the festival.
DM: Is that true?
DM: Uh, eh, I mean, you don't really know.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Um, you haven't...
DM: I mean, that is, it is,
DM: you know... Make an intelligence check.
Seeker: Not my strong suit.
Unknown: Uh.
DM: It's, you know, it's...
DM: Um, rem- you, which, you took the...
DM: Which, um,
DM: which background feature did you take?
DM: Worldly?
Unknown: Uh.
DM: Not-
DM: Not surveyor's eye.
Wellby: Uh, worldly I did.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Not surveyor's eye. Yep.
DM: Okay. So it's, yeah, it's har- eh, it's hard to say.
DM: I mean, it seems like vaguely the direction you came from when you first came to...
DM: And you know, it's not, there was some area out there that would be like grazing terrain, but it's eh.
DM: Right.
DM: You don't have a good sense.
Wellby: Well, I'll shout that back down. We got animal dust to the north, we got the big canyon to the east, and we've got a whole lot of mess between here or there with nothing moving
Wellby: and no obvious paths through.
Delwath: Uh, probably heading to the, uh,
Delwath: animal... To what...
Delwath: I mean, it's horses, we think?
DM: You can't see what's making it, it's just a cloud of dust.
DM: It could be hyenas for all you know.
DM: But if it were hyenas, they'd be running fast, right?
Delwath: Uh, I, I mean, okay, so in my experience just of life around the town, it's fairly un- Is, would it be like unusual for...
Delwath: We're kind of off the beaten path here, right?
DM: Um, so to the north...
DM: I mean, it wouldn't be impossible for that to be like Dunmari
DM: herders, right?
DM: That's the direction. This area, of course, nobody's taking animal through canyon lands, but, but north,
DM: um, sort of north of...
DM: You know, you would have heard people talking about the Gomat Oasis, which is kind of north and east of the town on the old trade road.
DM: So there used to be, uh, of course, lots of roads going through Dunmar.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Um, and, and it's, people don't like, pe- a lot of people don't u- typically go there because it's cl- it's like right on the edge of the blasted lands, um,
DM: that people sort of don't like to go into.
DM: But, um, it is, it is plausible pasture land, and that's roughly the direction,
DM: sort of the direction of where that Gomat Oasis might be.
DM: And so it, it's not, you'd say like 50/50 chance it's, it's Dunmari or more beasts.
Unknown: Well,
Delwath: I'll tell her, I mean,
Delwath: I think it's worth, uh, investigating, right?
Delwath: If it's more Dunmari, they might have seen something.
Delwath: If it's beasts,
Delwath: well, we've found something.
Seeker: Tim, it's not especially weird that there would be a canyon over in that other direction, is it?
Seeker: Is that, like, super unnatural?
DM: Uh, it's hard... I mean, if you could get closer to it, it would be easier for you to tell.
DM: Um, I think
DM: given the terrain here, it would certainly be plausible that there was a, a large na- that this sort of canyon lands-y area fed into a large natural canyon.
DM: Although, you haven't really got the sense that there's enough,
DM: enough running water. But, you know, it could be, you know, a river could easily be down in the bottom of a canyon to carve it out, and-
Seeker: Mm-hmm
DM: ... you know, feeding the oasis or something, and still there not be a lot of green plants here,
DM: right? It could just be like the Grand Canyon, right?
DM: Like, there's, it's desert all around.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But down at the bottom of the canyon there's some water.
DM: Mm-hmm.
DM: So it certainly would be plausible based on the terrain you are now, but you'd need to get closer to examine it carefully.
Seeker: Yeah, let's go check out the, the,
Seeker: the, uh, action.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So it looks like y- it's probably, you know,
DM: if you angle your dir- you could make a guesses to angle your direction of travel, so you would kind of cut off the whatever's moving up there.
DM: But it's not that far away.
DM: It's like an hour or two travel at most.
Wellby: Okay. Let's do it.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um, so you head sort of, now you're kind of heading northwest actually, um, because of the direction of travel of this, um,
DM: o- of this dust cloud, and kind of get back out of the canyon lands and, um, sort of head across the scrub desert.
Unknown: And
DM: as you get, as you get closer, um, you can, you can see when you're, um, not too far off that, um, this is
DM: a, it's definitely a Dunmarion horseback.
DM: Um, it's a
DM: younger woman riding at a medium trot who kind of notices you coming and, um, pulls up,
DM: and kind of looks at you a bit strangely, s- keeping her distance, and, um,
DM: and h- and sort of hails you in Dunmari.
DM: "Ho, travelers."
Delwath: Again, staying far away.
Delwath: I'll, I'll respond back, um, also in Dunmari, greeting her and telling her we, um, we've set out from...
Delwath: I'm blanking on the name. Kara- Karawa?
Unknown: Karawa.
Kenzo: Yep. Karawa.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: we've set out from Karawa, um,
Delwath: uh, in the last few hours, tracking some strange beasts.
Unknown: Um-
Delwath: Have you seen anything-
Unknown: Sh- she, like-
Delwath: ... out on the plains?
DM: ... looks at you all, and,
DM: you know, kind of a little bit taken aback by this sight, and stares at you in particular, um, Delwath.
Unknown: And then,
DM: uh, kind of thinks for a minute, and realization dawns on her and she says, "The elf.
DM: You must be the elf.
Delwath: Greetings."
Delwath: I nod slightly.
DM: "My name is Alesh.
Unknown: Uh,
Delwath: it is,
DM: um, it is unexpected to meet you out here.
Unknown: Uh,
DM: but interesting that you've
DM: reported strange beasts.
DM: Um, I am a, I'm a scout.
DM: I've been, uh, riding ahead.
DM: I'm returning from, um,
DM: investigating the area around the, the Gomat Oasis.
DM: Uh, there's been reports of people going missing, of herders and shepherds.
DM: And, um,
DM: I, I am concerned.
DM: There's strange rumors traveling among the scouts and pastoralists that are, um, you know, that wander in these lands.
DM: And despite the
DM: good quality of the grazing over there, um, you know, my family's been quite skeptical of, of heading in that direction without, uh,
DM: investigating. But I was just d- I was, I'm just riding, riding back from the Gomat Oasis itself, and have not seen anything the past day along the road.
Unknown: How-
DM: Where did you say you saw these animals?
Delwath: Uh, two, two hyenas the size of small horses.
Delwath: That's about right, right?
Unknown: Um-
DM: Uh, yeah
Kenzo: ... uh, were,
Delwath: uh, rampaging in Karawa, Karawa at dawn this morning.
DM: Um, she looks, she looks kind of, uh,
DM: um, shocked when you say that, and she, and, like, the blood drains from her face and she says,
DM: "Were people killed? I, I have family there.
DM: I have friends."
Delwath: No. M-
Delwath: One, one man was badly injured, but, um, he's under the care of the,
Delwath: of the Shakun now,
Delwath: and I believe will make a full recovery.
DM: Um, she, she kind of, um,
DM: relaxes a little bit and says...
DM: And, and she's now, she's sort of, um, inched closer to you as you've been talking, and moved, you know, from a, a, a stance of basically being ready to gallop away any second
Unknown: to, uh,
DM: um, to just kind of talking normally.
DM: Although, she's, she hasn't dismounted.
DM: She's still on her horse.
Unknown: Um,
DM: and sh- and she says, "And you're, you know, you're out here hunting the, these beasts?
DM: Do you, do you suspect there's more of them?
DM: Should w- should I be worried?"
Delwath: I think from of all you've just told us, yes.
DM: She kind of sighs a little bit and says,
DM: "It seemed,
DM: it seemed like maybe the danger was past.
DM: I had heard rumors, but I,
DM: I travel these roads quite frequently.
DM: There's..."
DM: Um, and her eyes light up a little and she says, "There's lots of old battle sites along these roads, and
DM: things to find, spears, arrows,
DM: shields sometimes.
Unknown: Uh,
DM: and although
DM: years ago in my childhood people would say, 'Oh, it's too dangerous,'
DM: um, it's, it's felt safer recently, and, and I've been on the r- I've been tr- ranging wide with my family over the
DM: past six months, and I did not realize
DM: the danger had, I guess, has returned."
Kenzo: What do you mean by has returned?
DM: Well, the, you know, the, people when, when I was a kid,
DM: when I was growing up 15, 20 years ago,
DM: people would go missing. We never, we never went into the, into the, um...
DM: Oops, sorry, hold on.
DM: We never went into the Nashtkar, the Blasted Plains.
DM: You know, as a, as a kid who tr- who traveled around here, I was, you know, you know there's a lot of history.
DM: And she, and she looks sort of specifically at...
DM: Well, she kind of looks at all of you, like, kind of questioning, you know, are, are these people interested in history?
Unknown: Um,
DM: and then looks at, at Kenzo, who is, uh, who is Dunmari.
DM: Um, who do I need to message?
Unknown: Uh.
Unknown: [coughs]
Kenzo: Do, do, uh, do Seeker and, um, uh, Wellby understand Dunmari?
DM: Yeah, everybody understands Dunmari.
DM: I just gave you all Dunmari 'cause it would be frustrating and annoying for n- you not to.
Kenzo: [laughs] Yeah.
Unknown: Um,
DM: yeah, so everybody understands Dunmari.
DM: I mean, Wellby's been traveling long enough and, and Seeker, you've both been traveling enough to have picked it up.
DM: And, um,
DM: uh, and she says, "So, you know, my,
DM: the, the history here is, is fascinating.
DM: I don't know how much you know about, well..."
DM: And then she kind of stops herself and, and looks at, um, looks at Delwath and says, "I guess the elf would know the most,
DM: more than me.
Unknown: Um,
DM: people say that you're very old."
Delwath: Delwath just kind of nods a bit.
DM: And, and then she says, um,
DM: "You know, but the, the
DM: history is so fascinating, and I, I was always told, 'Oh, don't go digging around those old graves.
DM: You don't know what you might find.
DM: Those battle sites are...
DM: Who knows what, what could still be there.'
DM: But it, but in the past few years, it's felt safer, and people have been grazing as far, actually east of, of Gomat, um, as far as the canyon even.
Unknown: Uh,
DM: but if what you said is true and danger is coming out of the east again, I fear that, that, um, you know, maybe those days of my childhood are coming back.
Wellby: There's a few..."
DM: Sorry, go ahead.
Wellby: Is there a path from the Gomat Oasis to the canyon that doesn't pass through the Badlands?
DM: Yeah, just follow the road east.
DM: You're now... I mean, you're on this ancient, this sort of old trade road where you can see occasionally, like, um, it's mostly just a track kind
DM: of kicked up through the, you know, s- through the sand, but every now and then there's, like, a paving stone or a, um, you know, kind of a, a little bit of ancient history
DM: suggesting that it's, um,
DM: uh, you know, uh...
DM: Uh, you can sort of, you can sense, you can sort of see the history of the road.
DM: Like, you can tell that this used to be, many, many years ago, well-traveled.
DM: It's just been worn down and broken up, and the, and the paving stones have all cracked and everything, but there's definitely a road you can follow.
DM: So the road'll take you straight to Gomat, and, and from there, um, there's not a, there's not a way across the canyon that I know of.
DM: The road sort of ends.
DM: But certainly it'll take you to the canyon.
DM: I've been as far as that before.
DM: In fact, there was a, just, um,
DM: just last night, I, I spent the night with a, a couple of, um, herding families and their flocks of sheep, uh, around Gomat,
DM: uh, and,
DM: and I, uh, uh, just came straight on the road this morning.
DM: It's, it's,
DM: you know, no more than a, a day's walk to the, to the oasis.
DM: Maybe two, depending on how fast you walk.
Unknown: Um,
DM: eight hours on, on a fast horse.
DM: But it'll take you straight through the, the canyon lands.
DM: I, I wouldn't wander south of here much.
DM: It's trackless there.
DM: It's... Sometimes even I get lost.
DM: Hm. Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Well, we seek the origins of these strange hyenas.
Kenzo: It's, uh,
Kenzo: unclear if you've seen anything related to their origin.
Kenzo: Sounds like you may not have.
DM: I haven't seen anything related to those, but strange beasts, I always say, must be the Blasted Lands.
Wellby: Would there be anyone...
Wellby: Oh, go ahead, sorry.
DM: Who knows what comes out of there?
Wellby: Hmm. Beside the Gomat Oasis and the road east toward the canyon from there, are there any families or herders
Wellby: or anyone east or east by northeast of here?
Wellby: No one goes-
Wellby: When the creature, when the creature came into town and had blood on it, that it
Wellby: must have come from somewhere.
DM: She looks,
DM: um, a little bit pale when you say that, and she says,
DM: "A straight line
DM: from Gomat to Karawa would pass through the edge of those canyon lands."
Wellby: I think we should push to the oasis.
DM: There were defi- there's definitely, you know,
DM: people coming in, gathering at Gomat and heading into Karawa for the,
DM: for the, um,
DM: for the festival. Uh, you said they attacked this morning?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: She kind of breathes a sigh of relief in, uh, when you say that, and she says,
DM: "They couldn't have traveled from Gomat to town in only a few hours,
DM: less than an hour. The f- the families that left this morning must be safe.
Unknown: But
DM: others around here,
DM: you do make, you do make me nervous."
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: I glance at the, the company.
Kenzo: Where do you think we should go?
Wellby: I think we should push to the oasis.
Wellby: If there's anyone who would have been out in this land, you know, to the east or to the northeast of here,
Wellby: presumably some word of that would have come to the people gathering at the oasis.
Wellby: I, I feel like that's our best bet-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... to learn more.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: How far, uh, how far is it from here to the oasis, based on what she was saying?
DM: So, I mean, she rode
DM: eight hours at a fast, fast pace.
DM: I think on foot,
DM: you know, traveling in relatively unfamiliar terrain, it would take you
DM: a day or two.
Unknown: Not-
DM: When is the festival?
DM: Festival's in like two weeks.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: It's, this is a bit far to stray,
Kenzo: given the time of the festival.
Wellby: Oh, sorry. Could we get there like by tomorrow night?
DM: You could, you could be at the...
Unknown: Eh,
DM: well, it's already like 4:00 in the afternoon by now.
DM: Um, you could get a few more hours tonight, um, travel all day.
DM: You probably wouldn't quite get there.
DM: Un- if you could push on into the night, you could get there past dark, for sure,
DM: if you made a long day of it tomorrow.
DM: But it would be dark.
Unknown: Um...
Kenzo: What do you say, travelers?
Delwath: Tim, I just asked you a m- a question.
DM: I see it. Um,
DM: sorry, I missed the earlier one.
Delwath: No, that one doesn't matter as much, but-
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: Tim, you saw the thing I sent you, right?
DM: Um, um, yes.
Kenzo: Okay.
Unknown: I did.
DM: Okay. Uh...
Kenzo: What say you, travelers?
DM: Sh- should we
Kenzo: continue onward to the oasis?
Seeker: Seems like the only reasonable course.
Kenzo: I worry about straying too far from town, but
Kenzo: I think if we, uh, investigate further there and...
Delwath: And, and how sure are we that
Delwath: nothing will come from another direction?
Wellby: Tell us about the last two attacks.
Wellby: Do you know where those came from or how far spaced they were?
Seeker: I was wondering about that.
Unknown: Uh...
Delwath: Tim, did you hear the question?
DM: Um, how far spaced are the attacks?
DM: Yeah. I, I don't know-
DM: Uh, they both happened, they both happened within the past two weeks.
Unknown: But they were like-
Delwath: But the previous-
DM: The first one was two weeks ago,
DM: and the next one was about six days after that, and then nothing for
DM: eight or nine, eight days, roughly.
Delwath: Hmm. But the previous attacks, the previous attacks were just, we all thought they were just wild, wild creatures.
Delwath: They were not these oversized beasts.
Wellby: Hmm.
Kenzo: Perhaps should we head back to town then in case, uh, another, another attack strikes again?
Kenzo: Without us, is the town defenseless?
Kenzo: I'm glancing at the company.
Delwath: It, it's not defenseless, but
Delwath: it's definitely not well defended either.
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: If we stay in town to defend it, though, there's no way for us to know the source or to try and track it.
Kenzo: Well, if we, if we make haste to the oasis, learn what, learn what we can there, uh, we can be back in, back to town in, what, two days, three days?
DM: If you push yourselves, yeah, you could be, if you, you could make it to the oasis by tomorrow night, and then it would take you a, a, you know, a day and a half, again,
DM: pushing yourself long, hard days to get back to town.
Kenzo: I'm new to the town. I, I'm new to Karawa.
Kenzo: I'm not, not familiar with its denizens or, or its defenses.
Kenzo: If you, if you feel like,
Kenzo: uh, our, our, uh, our absence
Kenzo: and our, our ability to learn more will, will be e- more useful,
Kenzo: I defer to, to you all who've been there longer.
Unknown: I think
Delwath: we should go to the oasis, but with haste.
Kenzo: All right then.
Kenzo: Um, I, I glance over at the Dunmari, uh, uh, horse rider.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: "Friend, what's your name?
Kenzo: I'm Kenzo. Also, also D- also Dunmari.
Kenzo: It's good to seem, see you here."
DM: Uh, her, her name is Alesh.
Unknown: Alesh.
Kenzo: Alesh,
Kenzo: my companions and I, I think we're gonna head to the oasis.
Kenzo: Are you safe here?
DM: You should be, you should be
Kenzo: careful. These are, these are dangerous times.
DM: I'm fast. There's few things that can catch me on my horse.
DM: She has, like, a pretty confident look.
DM: I mean, she was, you know, she looks-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... comf- very comfortable on horseback.
Unknown: Um,
DM: and she says, "And I need to get back to my family anyway.
DM: They've been, we've been, uh, looking for more pasture land that seems safe, and I'm not gonna take them east after hearing these stories.
DM: I think we're gonna head north for, for a bit more grazing and fatten up our, our animals before taking them into town for the festival."
Kenzo: Hm. Good.
Kenzo: Well then, safe travels.
Kenzo: Uh, please, please be safe.
DM: And
Unknown: if we-
Unknown: Um
Kenzo: ... we hear word in the oasis, uh, we'll...
Unknown: Actually,
Kenzo: are you, do you have friends in the oasis that you might recommend we speak with to learn more?
DM: Uh, uh, there was a f- there was a few, uh, uh, folks that I,
DM: I spent the night with.
DM: Um, they seemed, they seemed welcoming, and we traded stories.
DM: Uh, if you are, if you are looking for anybody, there's not a...
DM: There's, just to be clear, there's not a town there.
DM: It's like, it's, it's not a built-up oasis like Karawa.
DM: It's just a sort of a place where, where people set up camp for a week-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
DM: ... when they're grazing their animals and stuff.
DM: Um-
Kenzo: Oh, so it's not, like, permanent dwellings.
DM: It's not permanent dwellings, but, but, um, uh, when I was there, um, yeah, ask for, um, ask for Akan and his family.
DM: Um, they were camped there last night and were planning on spending a few more days, uh, grazing their herds there.
DM: Uh, and they seemed friendly and, and, and, uh, we shared some good stories.
Kenzo: Perfect. We'll seek them.
DM: Um, and as she's, she goes to ride off, uh, "I must," she says, "I must hurry," and then goes to ride off and then says, "And if you find any,
DM: any battle sites or any relics of ancient Dunmore, Dunmar, I'll be at the festival.
DM: Come find me. I'd be curious to know."
Unknown: Hm.
DM: And with that, she calls over her shoulder, "Stay safe," as she gallops off, um, down the road again.
Kenzo: Is there, is there, like, a Dunmari greeting or a farewell?
DM: Um, yeah, uh-
Kenzo: Whatever it is, I do. Whatever it is, I do it.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Um,
DM: how much longer do you guys wanna keep going, by the way?
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Should we wrap up and, like-
Unknown: I'm-
DM: ... you know, the next-
DM: ... pretty tired
DM: ... or, like, keep going a bit past that?
Kenzo: I think we could... I mean, this is a pretty good spot in a way.
Unknown: Like, we-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... could start up at the oasis.
Wellby: You know, like we-
Unknown: I think so, yeah
Kenzo: ... we arrive at the oasis.
DM: Yeah. Yeah, that's what I was thinking.
Unknown: That's-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... let's, that's, like, five or 10 minutes.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Cool. Okay.
Unknown: So,
DM: um, you set out,
DM: uh, heading towards the oasis, following the road.
DM: As you,
DM: as you travel, you can s- you get a sense of the, the sort of history of this place and how
DM: violent the cataclysms were that, that shook this land, as every now and then you'll see, you know, a stretch of, of, you know, stone tile that's not
DM: cracked, but a large stone paver that's just tilted straight upright, sitting vertical in the sand.
DM: And as you pass through this, um, this land, it's easy to follow the, the road, and when you come to the, um, to sort of the edge of the canyon lands, the road
DM: cuts straight,
DM: and it seems like it's been cleared, but more recently.
DM: This is not, um,
DM: this is not ancient. The canyon lands almost grew up around the road instead of the road being built through them.
DM: But there's places where, um, you know, dirt, sand and dirt and, and stone has been kind of pushed aside to make a path that at least a horse can travel single file
DM: through. Um, and this definitely is a, is a, um, a path that gets some, some traffic.
DM: You spend a cold, quiet night, um, sheltered off the road,
DM: long resting so you all get your spell slots back and everything, and your, get your charges back for your, the thing we were talking about earlier, Eric.
Unknown: Cool.
Unknown: Um,
DM: get up very early, pre-dawn the following day to, for, to press on, um, traveling as hard and fast as you can to get to
Delwath: the oasis.
DM: It's a long day, traveling in the heat of the sun.
DM: Um- ...
DM: pushing on, uh, into the, the moonlight evening.
DM: Um, can you all make constitution checks?
Kenzo: What?
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Why would we do that, Tim?
Kenzo: Damn it.
Wellby: [laughs] That's some good numbers.
DM: That's awesome.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Oh, shit.
DM: Oh, no.
Seeker: Oh, no.
Seeker: Delwath is fine.
Seeker: Uh, yeah.
Wellby: Can all three of us ride on the horse?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Well, no, one of you can ride on the horse, 'cause the horse is carrying, like, you know, all of your water and, you know, you're in the desert, right?
DM: You gotta travel with food and water and stuff like that.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: so
DM: in the moonlight,
DM: like, the heat of the day just beats down on you.
DM: The pushing yourself, exerting yourself in the desert, um,
DM: even those of you who are, who are used to traveling in these conditions, you are, you are pushing yourself, um, harder and, and further to get to this oasis
DM: as fast as you can.
DM: And, um,
DM: Wellby, Seeker, and Kenzo suffer one level of exhaustion from exerting yourself through the day.
Seeker: Um, how does that work?
DM: So that gives you disadvantage on ability checks.
Unknown: Um,
DM: not Delwath.
Delwath: No, I... Yeah, I was just playing.
Delwath: I was just seeing what it did.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Okay. Um,
DM: so it gives you disadvantage on ability checks until you t- until you get to sleep.
Seeker: Oh, do I have to do something?
Seeker: Sorry.
Unknown: Uh, if-
Delwath: If you click on your character sheet under conditions.
Delwath: Do you see where it says conditions?
Unknown: You can-
Delwath: You can scroll down, you go to exhausted, and you can click on level one.
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: Conditions.
Delwath: It's like-
Unknown: Exhausted. Got it
Delwath: ... next to defenses below your hit points.
DM: Oh, yeah, yeah. I'm seeing it now.
Seeker: Got it.
Seeker: Level one.
Seeker: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: So
DM: you get close to the oasis,
DM: see in the moonlight, um, the
DM: tents,
DM: and the quiet scene, palm trees swaying.
DM: A few, um, y- you hear the flapping in the breeze
DM: of the tents in f- of the, um, tents and the camp in front of you.
DM: There's no fire. It seems to be quiet,
DM: until you look around
DM: and you see-
Seeker: They're all dead
DM: ... in front of you, um-
Unknown: Mm-mm
DM: ... dead sheep.
Wellby: We turn around real quick.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Three, four of them.
DM: And in front of the sheep, like chewing on them in the darkness,
DM: three enormous lizards.
Unknown: Lizards?
DM: About, about the size of a small pony.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Much bigger than what you'd expect a lizard to be.
Unknown: Um,
DM: tearing into these things, seemingly unaware of your presence.
DM: And that's where we're gonna stop.
Seeker: Oh, snap.
DM: Mm.
Unknown: Ta-da.
Kenzo: Uh, all right.
Seeker: Mm.
DM: Mm. Giant lizards.
Unknown: Exciting.
DM: Pretty, pretty good.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: That was awesome.
Kenzo: Yeah, that was fun. Totally.
Unknown: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Nice to meet everybody's characters and everything, yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Feel like there's a lot more to unpack here, this is great.
Unknown: Um-
Delwath: Totally.
Kenzo: Mike and Tim?
Unknown: Yeah?
Kenzo: Can we, can we stay for, like, five minutes-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... and finish the conversation that we're having?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Yeah.
DM: Sure.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Um,
DM: okay. Awesome, guys. That was really fun.
DM: You totally skipped, like, 90% of what I prepared, but we'll come back to it later.
DM: Wa- how did we do that?
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Oh, no.
Unknown: Why?
Wellby: It seemed pretty direct.
Unknown: Um-
Delwath: I had no idea how we even managed to skip anything.
Delwath: We thought we were following the path laid out for us.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: No, it's good. It's great.
DM: I had a lot in town that you just-
Unknown: Ah [laughs]
DM: ... breezed past, but it'll all come to light eventually.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: This is what you get, Tim-
Unknown: Oh. [laughs]
Kenzo: ... for playing, for playing with us.
DM: But it was funny, I-
Unknown: You what?
Kenzo: No, I was just gonna say, as we were traveling, I was like...
Kenzo: I was just... I had a, a flashback to, um, you know, when our characters became so powerful that we could teleport anywhere we wanted.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] Oh, yeah.
Unknown: No-